<!-- This XML file does not appear to have any style information associated with it. The document tree is shown below. -->
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>lbhasemeyer</title>
<description>lbhasemeyer</description>
<link>https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/home</link>
<item>
<title>Around-the-World Packing List</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
I've had a lot of people ask what we packed for our trip. Today I stumbled upon this list and decided to post it to help any one else who is packing for an around-the-world trip, as well as for future me. This list includes everything we needed from the beaches of Thailand to the sub-zero temperatures of Nepal. We picked things up and left things behind, so this is an aggregate list of everything we needed at some point. The only things not listed are Mark's clothes, which I could probably list
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/31/Around-the-World-Packing-List
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/31/Around-the-World-Packing-List
</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 18:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>I've had a lot of people ask what we packed for our trip. Today I stumbled upon this list and decided to post it to help any one else who is packing for an around-the-world trip, as well as for future me. This list includes everything we needed from the beaches of Thailand to the sub-zero temperatures of Nepal. We picked things up and left things behind, so this is an aggregate list of everything we needed at some point. The only things not listed are Mark's clothes, which I could probably list from memory because I saw him in the same 5 shirts for over a year. The world in general is much more modest than the US (can't show your knees in Africa, no tank tops or shorts in rural Asia, 3-piece outfit required in Bangladesh...), something I quickly learned and adjusted my pack to. MISCELLANEOUS: 60L backpacking bag and rain-cover small fold-up daypack 40 degree sleeping bag mosquito net (we used this a lot) phone (to use with sim cards and listen to music) earbuds iPad (for blog writing) camera chargers Steripen (to sterilize water - we used this daily.) head lamp batteries waterproof watch deck of cards notebook &amp; pen money belt - driver's license, passport, credit card, ATM card copies of documents and cards for backpack diving logs, diving card (for scuba) sunglasses TOILETRIES: toothbrush &amp; toothpaste travel size shampoo, conditioner, soap (refilled as we went) deodorant quick-dry towel (very small) razor comb toilet paper (this is key) DIVA cup travel size bug spray travel size sunscreen hand sanitizer tiger-balm (to put under your nose if stuck in a place with bad smells for days) hair ties ear plugs (for loud overnight bus rides) tweezers nail clippers MEDICINE: very basic 1st aid kit, pack of electrolyte powder (for bad digestive issues) pills - birth control, malaria, cipro, Ibuprofen, high altitude medicine, motion sickness medicine CLOTHES: down jacket rain jacket gloves, snow pants (for Everest basecamp) thermal long-sleeve 3 T-shirts 2 tank tops capri yoga pants leggings knee-length skirt athletic shorts floor-length black skirt (for temples, churches, etc.) black loose athletic pants (for modest countries) traditional 3-piece outfit (purchased in Bangladesh, also used in India) 2 dresses - 1 modest pashmina scarf hat 3 pairs of socks (one extra warm) 1 swimsuit 4 pairs of quick-dry underwear 2 sports bras, 1 bra SHOES: Chaco sandals (waterproof, good for hiking, durable) flat Target sandals (to look nicer) hiking boots</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Obligatory Reflection - Boulder, CO</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
After almost a month of being back, it's time for the obligatory end-of-trip reflection. As my great friend Hannah said, "I'm excited to observe and see how travel changed you". While that makes me feel a bit like a lab rat, I have to agree that I am curious to see how I have grown. A few things I know I have learned so far are that: I LOVE free bathrooms that are not covered in spiders and bugs coming up through the hole an empty cement room with a trough on one end door-less and TP-less so
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/11/The-Obligatory-Reflection---Boulder-CO
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/11/The-Obligatory-Reflection---Boulder-CO
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 19:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>After almost a month of being back, it's time for the obligatory end-of-trip reflection. As my great friend Hannah said, &quot;I'm excited to observe and see how travel changed you&quot;. While that makes me feel a bit like a lab rat, I have to agree that I am curious to see how I have grown. A few things I know I have learned so far are that: I LOVE free bathrooms that are not covered in spiders and bugs coming up through the hole an empty cement room with a trough on one end door-less and TP-less so stinky I almost pass out If Mark and I made it through one year of being together 24/7, along with various digestive and other unflattering issues, I am very optimistic for our future. I am very assertive. It must be something about people trying to scam you, creepy men, bargaining, and having to deal with different issues daily, but I now don't take crap from anyone. Watch out! We are really lucky to be from the USA. We maintain a much higher standard of living than the rest of the world. We don't have thousands of soldiers walking around town with fingers on gun triggers, we don't live in mud huts, and we have endless opportunities to guide our lives in the direction that makes us happiest. It is important to remember how blessed we are, and to give generously to those who aren't as lucky. Travel is worth every penny. It's true we would be MUCH better off financially if we hadn't done this trip, but we have absolutely no regrets spending it all. --- Our favorite countries (although we disagree on the order) are Myanmar, Nepal, and Bangladesh. Our least favorite was India (due to our interactions with the people - although we were only in the big cities). Although they did have some of the best food. Our favorite foods came from Mexico, India, and Israel. The worst food was in Myanmar (Funny how Myanmar/India were exact opposites when it comes to food versus overall awesomeness). The country that was hardest to communicate in was Brazil. The coolest language was Ethiopian - google it, it's crazy. Now that we have more-or-less settled into our Boulder condo, we have exciting life news (...no, we are not pregnant). I have decided to go to a 6-month website development school on Pearl Street. There's a guaranteed job at the end, and I am so excited to learn something new! Also, Mark just accepted an excellent big-boy job at Seagate, a big hard drive company near home. Hello, real world! Anyways, that's the best reflection I can do right now. Time to chug a coffee and continue preparing our 2013 taxes :) Excited to see all of you (in person) soon!!</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>VIDEO: El Final</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
The end is near. The end is here. Copy and paste this in your browser to watch: http://youtu.be/BIryDzlNxXg Miss part 3? http://youtu.be/9bjEfba6YBE Miss part 2? http://youtu.be/G2_a9STvLeU Miss part 1? http://youtu.be/1wEK9AXv56Q
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/10/VIDEO-El-Final
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/10/VIDEO-El-Final
</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>The end is near. The end is here. Copy and paste this in your browser to watch: http://youtu.be/BIryDzlNxXg Miss part 3? http://youtu.be/9bjEfba6YBE Miss part 2? http://youtu.be/G2_a9STvLeU Miss part 1? http://youtu.be/1wEK9AXv56Q</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Home Again, Home Again, Jiggedy Jig! - Denver, CO</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We had planned to surprise our parents by having our siblings invite them to dinner at the same restaurant. We told them we would arrive three days later, so we were looking forward to seeing their shocked faces when we walked in. The flight from Corpus Christi to Dallas was delayed but worked out fine. Our flight from Dallas to Denver, however, was diverted to land at Colorado Springs due to bad weather closing DIA. We joined a slew of other planes there, waiting for the hourly update to hear
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2017/07/03/Home-Again-Home-Again-Jiggedy-Jig---Denver-CO
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2017/07/03/Home-Again-Home-Again-Jiggedy-Jig---Denver-CO
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We had planned to surprise our parents by having our siblings invite them to dinner at the same restaurant. We told them we would arrive three days later, so we were looking forward to seeing their shocked faces when we walked in. The flight from Corpus Christi to Dallas was delayed but worked out fine. Our flight from Dallas to Denver, however, was diverted to land at Colorado Springs due to bad weather closing DIA. We joined a slew of other planes there, waiting for the hourly update to hear if DIA was open. Finally, three hours and a federally required &quot;extended delay&quot; snack later, we flew to DiA. We were forced to call the parents and tell them we were in Colorado but the dinner was off. Major bummer. Of course the day we returned to Denver was the only time we have ever been significantly delayed on our trip. Go figure. Anyways, we got picked up, grabbed a Chipotle (mine was free because the guy was so impressed we came straight there from the airport), and went to Matt and Emily's new house (my brother and his wife) to hang out with everyone and eat dessert. It was a stressful and disappointing day, but in the end we were so happy to be able to see our famlilies. Mark and I have started moving and also begun the job/school hunt. It's good to be home :) Domesticated life here we come!</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Where Everything's Bigger - Corpus Christi, Texas, United States
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We took the last few days of our trip to visit Mark's brother, Brad, and his girlfriend, Camilia. Checking our bag in Mazatlan earned us a fee. At least we only have one now! I was also not allowed to carry my new tortilla press onto the plane...in Mexico. Something about it being a weapon. We were only given soft-drinks on our international flight from Mazatlan to Dallas. American Airlines, and airlines in America in general, are the worst in the world. Immigration at the Dallas airport was<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_29163772a3e042ccbd6b1de371aaec50%7Emv2_d_6000_4000_s_4_2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/09/Where-Everythings-Bigger---Corpus-Christi-Texas-United-States
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/09/Where-Everythings-Bigger---Corpus-Christi-Texas-United-States
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 18:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We took the last few days of our trip to visit Mark's brother, Brad, and his girlfriend, Camilia. Checking our bag in Mazatlan earned us a fee. At least we only have one now! I was also not allowed to carry my new tortilla press onto the plane...in Mexico. Something about it being a weapon. We were only given soft-drinks on our international flight from Mazatlan to Dallas. American Airlines, and airlines in America in general, are the worst in the world. Immigration at the Dallas airport was (ironically) the least organized we have seen in our whole year traveling. Hoards of people, confusion, hours in line, and unfriendly faces were our warm welcome back to the USA. We met a famous boxing announcer and spent time chatting until I noticed he was taking (what he thought were) indiscreet photos of me on his phone. I called him out and made him delete them. Then Mark lost his Colorado hat (that he had somehow held on to the whole year) in the Corpus Christi airport. But the day wasn't all bad. Our long layover in Dallas meant that we had time to scarf down Qdoba burritos (Chipotle has to wait until Colorado). Mark re-filled his coke with a giant smile on his face - he's been looking forward to bottomless soda for months. We also drank from water fountains, used provided toilet paper, and washed our hands with warm water. Go America! After a day of flying it was great to see Brad and Camilia! Brad had a serious burn accident at work (he is a mechanic) a few months ago. He is sporting some serious wounds that are not done healing, but is doing much, much better. We relaxed at their house, did some chores (like write this blog), saw the new house they just bought nearby (it's still being constructed but is the best looking on the block), and cooked a mean taco meal with our new tortilla press. I gained back most of the weight lost on the trip. It was a good intro back to America. Our last night we went to the new Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles movie. Or as one article I agree with put it, &quot;The Megan Fox Show&quot;. Other than her face always being on the screen in a model pout, it was pretty wonderful. Next stop Boulder!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_29163772a3e042ccbd6b1de371aaec50~mv2_d_6000_4000_s_4_2.jpg"/><div>Finally...A Tex-Mex Burrito...Yum</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0db48e39db8b4dd08fad60a17b5a88b8~mv2_d_6000_4000_s_4_2.jpg"/><div>Free refills!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6da470b51d2e466ca63d38f2acd29cc2~mv2_d_6000_4000_s_4_2.jpg"/><div>Reunited</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>
2 Year Wedding Anniversary - Mazatlán, Sinaloa, Mexico
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Due to all Mazatlan hostels and hotels being full of vacationing Mexicans, Mark and I found an Airbnb in the spare room of a woman's house. She was friendly, gave us towels for the beach, mangos, and a delicious homemade breakfast of mango smoothie, yogurt, tortillas, rice, beans, and veggies. Yum. The city used to have dozens of cruise ships stop daily, but after the reputation in the area for drugs, the tourism stopped. Recently things have been picking up again, especially as a place for<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dee23ada9f3a4e81b8b374ea714216dd%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/05/2-Year-Wedding-Anniversary---Mazatl%C3%A1n-Sinaloa-Mexico
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/05/2-Year-Wedding-Anniversary---Mazatl%C3%A1n-Sinaloa-Mexico
</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 19:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Due to all Mazatlan hostels and hotels being full of vacationing Mexicans, Mark and I found an Airbnb in the spare room of a woman's house. She was friendly, gave us towels for the beach, mangos, and a delicious homemade breakfast of mango smoothie, yogurt, tortillas, rice, beans, and veggies. Yum. The city used to have dozens of cruise ships stop daily, but after the reputation in the area for drugs, the tourism stopped. Recently things have been picking up again, especially as a place for locals to come on holiday. It's a nice city with a cute main square and goofy matching boxy giant golf cart-like taxis. Our day and night in Mazatlan also happened to be exactly on our 2-year wedding anniversary. To celebrate we relaxed at the beach, walked around town, showered, watched Mythbusters, ate nachos, and went to a shfancy restaurant (El Presidio) recommended to us by Mark's cousin. It was set in a re-done abandoned building, with a beautiful courtyard full of lights and vines. One of the prettiest places I have ever eaten. The food was delicious, and brought to the table in bird cages. Yes, bird cages. Very hipster-classy of them. We ate so much that we almost puked.</div><div>Picnic</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dee23ada9f3a4e81b8b374ea714216dd~mv2.jpg"/><div>Stoked</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5cb4631e3c9c43dfb7818f6ca65cb67f~mv2.jpg"/><div>Sandy Hair</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a453a2ec4a194154965f3a195a168ff3~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Culiacan - Culiacán Rosales, Sinaloa, Mexico</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
From Queretaro we bussed back to Mexico City to catch a flight to Culiacan. You've probably heard about it in the news for its drug problems? My Aunt Blanca, Uncle Dave, and cousins (David and Ximena) live there. But they are not drug lords (I don't think). It was great to be around familiar sights and faces again. It was like a vacation from a vacation. David and Ximena had a baby girl, Danika, about a year ago. Probably the cutest and toughest girl you'll ever see. And last but not least -<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8193bb9b28ad4f1c9fb4667c48668dfd%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/04/Culiacan---Culiac%C3%A1n-Rosales-Sinaloa-Mexico
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/08/04/Culiacan---Culiac%C3%A1n-Rosales-Sinaloa-Mexico
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>From Queretaro we bussed back to Mexico City to catch a flight to Culiacan. You've probably heard about it in the news for its drug problems? My Aunt Blanca, Uncle Dave, and cousins (David and Ximena) live there. But they are not drug lords (I don't think). It was great to be around familiar sights and faces again. It was like a vacation from a vacation. David and Ximena had a baby girl, Danika, about a year ago. Probably the cutest and toughest girl you'll ever see. And last but not least - Jayden. He's my cousin Bianca's kid. I guess that makes him a first cousin once removed? We had a debate about it. They were all incredible hosts, making sure we got every taste of Mexico possible. The first day we spent eating. And not much else. Ceviche, raspados (Mexican snow cones), and pizza. Raspados make American snow cones look like baby food. These suckers are loaded up with all sorts of options. Fresh fruit juice, coconut, and dulce de leche to name a few. Then they soak the top with condensed milk. Mmm... mmm.... diabetes. After, we ate pizza at a restaurant overlooking the city and mountains. Here we saw one of (if not) the best sunsets I've seen in my life. Even the kitchen staff took a break from making pizza to come out and watch it. Unfortunately we forgot the camera, leaving you with a cell phone picture. The next morning we had yet another incredible meal and my Aunt and Uncle's house. Chilaquiles. And later that afternoon they took us to Altata, a small town on the coast where a lot of Mexicans go for spring break. They have a beach house there that I visited a lot growing up. It was fun showing Laura part of my childhood and reminiscing. Except the mosquitos. I conveniently forgot about them. We ate an awesome seafood dinner on the boardwalk and took a boat out into the Sea of Cortez where we saw some dolphins! The rest of our stay included more incredible food. Mainly tacos. Carnitas, goat, innards, head, seafood. If it's a meat, we probably ate it in a taco. David and Ximena also bought us a tortilla maker so we can make fresh corn tortillas for tacos at home! Turns out it's not that hard. After a few crispified tortillas we had it down to an art. We also relaxed at the neighborhood pool a few times and went to a local soccer game. It was a tie game, but we had fun hanging out drinking Tacate. Nights were spent playing competitive games of Monopoly and Apples to Apples and drinking margaritas. Overall, life was very good and as Uncle Dave would say, &quot;Welcome to semi-civilization!&quot;</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8193bb9b28ad4f1c9fb4667c48668dfd~mv2.jpg"/><div>Family Boat</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8ae3da495ce94fda8806c42953507135~mv2.jpg"/><div>Goat Tacos!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9bea7dbb415d4a928d31b2cb505c4659~mv2.jpg"/><div>Adorable Danika</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_52418425a1ce4dd5a7f108dc51044fbe~mv2.jpg"/><div>Altata House</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_86caea208d644d80926bae83dc8c07a6~mv2.jpg"/><div>Dolphins with Birds</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f1e02aabc4244fcfb3ca0a4ace940f4f~mv2.jpg"/><div>Altata - Freshest Seafood</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b9d141ccd68b4240b7359748f694e9d2~mv2.jpg"/><div>Happy Family</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b2157374380243e889273580c3dd9681~mv2.jpg"/><div>Beautiful Sunset</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Queretaro - Queretaro, Mexico</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We bussed from the Queretaro bus station to our hostel, dropped off our things, then went out for some late night tacos. Absolutely delicious. I don't think Mexican tacos could ever get old. Then we fell asleep. In our dorm room...not at the taco stand. Our hostel, the Blue Bicycle, is run by three middle-aged women and is spotless. There is a terrace overlooking the city, hot showers, towels, a delicious breakfast, free bicycle rentals, and the whole thing is new and beautiful. We are so glad<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2f77e42c113f42f3a006704661278861%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/28/Queretaro---Queretaro-Mexico
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/28/Queretaro---Queretaro-Mexico
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 18:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We bussed from the Queretaro bus station to our hostel, dropped off our things, then went out for some late night tacos. Absolutely delicious. I don't think Mexican tacos could ever get old. Then we fell asleep. In our dorm room...not at the taco stand. Our hostel, the Blue Bicycle, is run by three middle-aged women and is spotless. There is a terrace overlooking the city, hot showers, towels, a delicious breakfast, free bicycle rentals, and the whole thing is new and beautiful. We are so glad we went. Mark found a walking tour map of the historic center, and became &quot;Tour-guide Mark&quot; for the day. We saw a dozen churches, a dozen plazas, and lots of cool artisanal things. Lunch was delicious tortas (sandwiches filled with meat, cheese, and salsa). We also saw a group exercise session in the park, which looked more like a native dance. People danced to one loud drum, wore noisemakers on their legs, and spun in semi-coordinated unison. It was extremely entertaining. The city is beautiful and green and old (in a good way). Well, at least the part we are in. It's actually the second biggest city in Mexico. We love it. We spent the evening in our hostel writing blogs and watching Breaking Bad (we finally have internet fast enough to watch a show). And of course...we got more Mexican food.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_69b6c45f0da0495fa49b9702825ecc36~mv2.jpg"/><div>Puking Dog Fountain</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2f77e42c113f42f3a006704661278861~mv2.jpg"/><div>Tortas</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4d81379581f141beb1f70288f322c8ce~mv2.jpg"/><div>Shopping Street</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ce5d0ffab629433089168eac040b7d2b~mv2.jpg"/><div>One of Many Churches</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4ab2822bf74643faafec23e9a1179fc0~mv2.jpg"/><div>Beautiful Plaza</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a258a698dc534f5d90047c38dc72516c~mv2.jpg"/><div>Night View of Aquaducts</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_67ca52963fa743df99101024c1c280c2~mv2.jpg"/><div>Mural</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_189817f3264b4109a9a7a19bfcfe03a6~mv2.jpg"/><div>Schnazzy McDonalds</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>
San Miguel de Allende - San Miguel de Allende, Mexico
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We parted from Fran for the weekend to go checkout the beautiful city of San Miguel. But we should have planned our departure better... We arrived Friday night during a Film Festival. Apparently it's the busiest weekend of the year. Finding accommodation was like finding an English speaker in Brazil. We walked around for 2 hours until we finally convinced someone outside of town to let us in for only one night at a highly inflated price. By the time we found a place and settled in it was<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0796d6c36a714bf78cdc9df1cdf33cf2%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2017/07/03/San-Miguel-de-Allende---San-Miguel-de-Allende-Mexico
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2017/07/03/San-Miguel-de-Allende---San-Miguel-de-Allende-Mexico
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 18:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We parted from Fran for the weekend to go checkout the beautiful city of San Miguel. But we should have planned our departure better... We arrived Friday night during a Film Festival. Apparently it's the busiest weekend of the year. Finding accommodation was like finding an English speaker in Brazil. We walked around for 2 hours until we finally convinced someone outside of town to let us in for only one night at a highly inflated price. By the time we found a place and settled in it was midnight, and we were NOT in the mood to party. Bed. The next morning we walked around the city looking for accommodation for that evening. Nothing. So we said screw it and bought a bus ticket to Queretaro, another city about an hour and a half away. Laura has a friend there, so we were hoping to visit anyway. Our bus wasn't until that evening, so we still had a chance to see the &quot;oh so beautiful&quot; San Miguel. It was okay... It has a really cool church. I think we were bitter the whole day because we felt like we bussed there only to get turned around. Lots of schnazzy looking people were wandering the streets as if they were about to walk the red carpet (they're actually was a red carpet at the Film Festival). Laura and I felt... poor. So to fit in we went to a fancy hotel and bought mojitos. But they were on happy hour so I guess we didn't do that good of a job. After some more aimless wondering and picture taking, we headed back to the bus station and caught a ride to Queretaro. Good riddance San Miguel!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0796d6c36a714bf78cdc9df1cdf33cf2~mv2.jpg"/><div>It's Her Wedding Day!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_452bf0b40a3e4fdba6e8278f23ef63b0~mv2.jpg"/><div>Mas Graffiti</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b439e13eed2c412a91b38c0790528963~mv2.jpg"/><div>Purty House</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_80dca55006864d52a4c95861f83455fa~mv2.jpg"/><div>At the Corner</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2d8f41050ed14a3c85483fd0d3dbd0ed~mv2.jpg"/><div>Mojitos Were Drank Here</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dfb4681dd5e44d7d9aaf7bcd61610d21~mv2.jpg"/><div> Fancy.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_df82b89600a6460da49dd9aeebb44c6d~mv2.jpg"/><div>Seriously Disney </div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_93b06c68ed06459bac1d1819406581d6~mv2.jpg"/><div> Starbucks</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_63cac48bbab546b8b21e542323d06fb6~mv2.jpg"/><div>Love this. </div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5fa9036d7759473d9aeb58e3493cd01a~mv2.jpg"/><div> Sweet Car</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7ca07d7b4a55496ab02fa45fe5142352~mv2.jpg"/><div> Kids' Paradise</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_365f57027e3141b5a2457c2921e78a3d~mv2.jpg"/><div> Red Carpet</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2de5d0c491274630b161f0096dd49f87~mv2.jpg"/><div> Ballin'</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a9494619681b4b7b923c56bee063c372~mv2.jpg"/><div>Inside</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mexico City - Mexico City, Mexico</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Our friend Fran picked us up at the airport early in the morning after two layovers and 26 hours of travel. Mexico City is ENORMOUS! It's the third biggest in the world in terms of area, so we were never able to see the city limits. They also have giant flags all over town that I am pretty sure would completely crush numerous cars if detached from their flagpoles. Fran lives in a beautiful house with his dad, step mom, step sister, and a german shephard, "Hans". Hans gets his exercise by running<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1b2e479c97ab45639720f3b27a954a73%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/25/Mexico-City---Mexico-City-Mexico
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/25/Mexico-City---Mexico-City-Mexico
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Our friend Fran picked us up at the airport early in the morning after two layovers and 26 hours of travel. Mexico City is ENORMOUS! It's the third biggest in the world in terms of area, so we were never able to see the city limits. They also have giant flags all over town that I am pretty sure would completely crush numerous cars if detached from their flagpoles. Fran lives in a beautiful house with his dad, step mom, step sister, and a german shephard, &quot;Hans&quot;. Hans gets his exercise by running next to the car, going over 35 mph. Their home is in one of the nicest neighborhoods in Mexico City. The neighboring houses include a castle that was brought over from Germany and re-assembled, the owner of General Electric, and dozens of luxury cars. We were in an Alfa Romeo for the week. Fran also has a bodyguard who is ex-police and ex-military. He followed us around for almost all of our stay, staying an indiscreet 20-30 feet behind us. Don't mess with Fernando. After dropping our bags at his house, we all went for quesadillas and fried cow brain tacos. Surprisingly tasty. Then came the city tour of old town. We saw the Presidential Palace, a really old church that is slowly sinking (Mexico City is built on a lake), some pyramid ruins, and one of the downtown outdoor shopping streets. Included were meat and cheese tapas and delicious chocolate truffles. Fran's dad owns four (soon to be five) Italian restaurants in the city. We went to his restaurant that night and were treated to an absolutely delicious meal. Stuffed and exhausted, we went home and fell asleep at 7 PM. We didn't wake up for thirteen hours. Day two started with a trip to Xochimilco. It can best be described as a float down the river in colorful boats with mariachi bands, potato chips with hot sauce, and beer...with hot sauce (michelada). The Mexicans love to party on the boats there - even when we went at 10:00 AM. After our relaxing float we grabbed chocolate croissants and went to the swanky part of town to look at diamonds and meet Fran's mom for sushi. I even ate a plain slab of raw fish. I was very proud. Fran's Dad took us out to dinner that night. We went to a giant cafeteria with delicious tacos, horchata, and crazy Mexico juice: Jamaica. I can't stop smiling with all the delicious Mexican food here. It is long overdue. Day three welcomed us with delicious (and enormous) ham and cheese tacos. We then drove through an enormous park downtown to a real-life historical castle, Chapultepec. It is on top of a hill overlooking the whole city. Fran's great-grandpa made the cricket sculpture in the garden - turns out he was quite the artist. After getting our fill of castle, we went to a hipster market to get our fill of tacos, champagne, and Mezcal. We then went to a friend (Lulu)'s bakery for chocolate croissants, and then Fran's dads restaurant. That night we went to the mall. The next morning we get more chocolate croissants, then went to some circle pyramids in the middle of town. They were empty and beautiful. We took the afternoon to relax. Then Frans dad treated the three of us to dinner at a beautiful old hacienda called the San Angel Inn. I was shocked at how beautiful it was. One of the most beautiful restaurants I've ever been in. We ate ant eggs (which were surprisingly large), ribeye tacos, and I had one of the best margaritas of my life. The nest day Fran's mom picked us up to go to the Xochicalco pyramids an hour outside town. The complex was ENORMOUS. And supposedly only 1/10th of it has been uncovered. You could climb the pyramids, and even go inside them to see the room where the Aztecs used to monitor the sun. Then we were off to Taxco, one of Mexico's &quot;magic cities&quot;. It is famous for silver, and it's quaint white buildings sprawl over a mountainside. We met a 13-year old tour guide who joined us for parking, lunch (he ordered a steak without hesitation), shopping, and a church tour by his brother. We passed out as soon as we got home, and were invited to Fran's mom's house for breakfast our last morning before going to the bus station. Fruit, yogurt, chocolate croissants (yet again), chilaquiles, and huevos rancheros. YUM. Our time with Fran was amazing. We felt spoiled - make that we were spoiled, and got a first-class tour of Mexico City. Excited for him to visit Colorado in December so we can repay the kindness.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1b2e479c97ab45639720f3b27a954a73~mv2.jpg"/><div>Hans</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_19981b1943db4f5da54a347fc0a5a40b~mv2.jpg"/><div>Slug Bug Taxis</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_bb510f52ab7e480ba98709dd51cecc87~mv2.jpg"/><div>Church in Taxco</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a87ff617493e4e91a8b64845cb12148a~mv2.jpg"/><div>Taxco</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3155159c44a3416e9b12063f17403b6e~mv2.jpg"/><div>Friends</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d81ec7929a28473fbf2b758132e918d5~mv2.jpg"/><div>Lunch on the Terrace</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2f0f221bda594203ae0fe5384c83a5c5~mv2.jpg"/><div>View from Lunch</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f384d4264b494e018c41ed4fa1835c97~mv2.jpg"/><div>&quot;Yo&quot;</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_071ac2ff54d1432aa0fe09653e2ca441~mv2.jpg"/><div>Attack!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_683985d945ad4a49b79517bc6d6495ac~mv2.jpg"/><div>Ball Court</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_381ee40e65a84e908aa1dda2ad3a7549~mv2.jpg"/><div>All This Will Be Yours, Simba</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ccd2571355c3463eb028c9edf7f2ef85~mv2.jpg"/><div>Fran and His Momma</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ab410c38afbc476b9f86099878a5cdb4~mv2.jpg"/><div>Whoa</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_95dd865b08694312adb44c152d8a1e80~mv2.jpg"/><div>Bah!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b008187d922d40ec99a8deac5f500524~mv2.jpg"/><div>Xochicalco Pyramid</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a98c8f7d83ba446695baec572fe22389~mv2.jpg"/><div>Circle Pyramid</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a70c6f87a23247d3b0048b77c0afa9da~mv2.jpg"/><div>Top of the World!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6be23169a09744f49bbdb42df370bf62~mv2.jpg"/><div>Men</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_93015f6f820d4849843a0b6374929333~mv2.jpg"/><div>Mezcal</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_fe1ce2aa2f8f4b73b7904e684328b78f~mv2.jpg"/><div>Crazy Tamarind Candies</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Calle de Muerte - Sucre, Bolivia</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We left Cochabamba late at night and arrived in familiar La Paz around 5 AM. Our previous hostel was completely booked, so we settled for one down the street. We ate breakfast, passed out, and the signed up for "Calle de Muerte" (Road of Death) the next day. Calle de Muerte is an old dirt road that used to be a major transport link between La Paz and the surrounding valley. There are many tight turns (without guard rails) next to steep cliffs. Apparently you can still see wreckage if you look<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_083bf398426b4143a38aee573fe58b6a%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/19/Calle-de-Muerte---Sucre-Bolivia
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/19/Calle-de-Muerte---Sucre-Bolivia
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 18:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We left Cochabamba late at night and arrived in familiar La Paz around 5 AM. Our previous hostel was completely booked, so we settled for one down the street. We ate breakfast, passed out, and the signed up for &quot;Calle de Muerte&quot; (Road of Death) the next day. Calle de Muerte is an old dirt road that used to be a major transport link between La Paz and the surrounding valley. There are many tight turns (without guard rails) next to steep cliffs. Apparently you can still see wreckage if you look off some of the cliffs, hence the name: Death Road. We didn't see any wreckage, but we did see graves. Thankfully now there's a new, safer road that the Bolivians use leaving Death Road to be repurposed to tourists.... and downhill mountain biking. Groovy baby. We were picked up at 6am and traveled for an hour or so to the top of the valley. Here, were sized up for the proper mountain bike (Rocky Mountain Bicycle frames might I add). Then we began the high speed decent. The beginning is paved and is part of the new road that replaced Calle de Muerte. It was freezing! Laura and I were 99% sure our fingers were going to fall off. But eventually we hit the traditional dirt road which slowed things down. In addition to the lower altitude, things warmed up quick. We zigged and zagged through waterfalls and rivers, and dodged numerous cliff sides. It sounds scary, but when you're as pro as Laura and I, it ain't no thang. In total, the decent was more than 10,000 feet and took approximately two and a half hours. At the end we celebrated with a beer and ate lunch at a nice hotel. Then it was back to the city for a final meal before our flight to Mexico! Laura insisted that she get one more fresh squeezed orange juice and a bag of chocolate covered raisins before we go. I don't think we ever mentioned it, but there's fresh juice everywhere in Bolivia.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_083bf398426b4143a38aee573fe58b6a~mv2.jpg"/><div>Drop-off</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6379f4f0a87e46e0a30c6bc42f4a0176~mv2.jpg"/><div>Joy</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a5138b04128340008b609a129b5c84b6~mv2.jpg"/><div>The Trail</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_77e7acca3902449c80603d955aeea375~mv2.jpg"/><div>Down We Go!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8d120426b8b2457c88325777009dd59c~mv2.jpg"/><div> Zoom!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ec3e98be18294f91aaefd93d4d6a1517~mv2.jpg"/><div> Tunnel</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3e5044a19f754046a3934a35c8e182ca~mv2.jpg"/><div> Rolling</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5b06859bf91a409e8798104d76cc844c~mv2.jpg"/><div>Here We Go!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a0402a3c5cd042809b02975b824db99f~mv2.jpg"/><div>Grr</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2995d41c7f684281b3768f4a1980addc~mv2.jpg"/><div>Ready to Roll</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_32fecc5ff45d4c3a94e989f5850c3f7a~mv2.jpg"/><div>Water Falling</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_43651cd66345488e8325927af3ca58fa~mv2.jpg"/><div>Cold Morning</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_82b28f2630ee4d26aadd9b8fbadc6cf1~mv2.jpg"/><div> Morning Briefing</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1a7440553cf9440a8b0824e1a0d58df3~mv2.jpg"/><div>It's a Good Day </div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_564d73727a21482fa2086dd6c76ac343~mv2.jpg"/><div>Extreme</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Visiting Beiba (no, not Justin Beiber) - Cochabamba, Bolivia
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
At 4:30AM, we rolled into Cochabamba. It is definitely more of a working city than a tourist city, thus our hostel was located more in the "suburbs". We took a taxi from the bus station in the center of the city to our hostel. When we arrived, we were stopped by concrete walls and a big black gate. Like good civilized people, we rang the doorbell and waited for an answer. Five minutes later, a man opened the door revealing a huge compound within. Green grass, trees, and hammocks. It was like<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b8057f80c44f44d5a042f960dd4ddb69%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/14/Visiting-Beiba-no-not-Justin-Beiber---Cochabamba-Bolivia
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/14/Visiting-Beiba-no-not-Justin-Beiber---Cochabamba-Bolivia
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 18:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>At 4:30AM, we rolled into Cochabamba. It is definitely more of a working city than a tourist city, thus our hostel was located more in the &quot;suburbs&quot;. We took a taxi from the bus station in the center of the city to our hostel. When we arrived, we were stopped by concrete walls and a big black gate. Like good civilized people, we rang the doorbell and waited for an answer. Five minutes later, a man opened the door revealing a huge compound within. Green grass, trees, and hammocks. It was like taking a portal to another planet. But considering how early it was, we decided to hit the sack rather than mingle with nature. The next day we hit up the local supermarket and looked for a few presents for the next day (keep reading and it will make sense). Then we relaxed. And it was awesome. On Monday, we waited outside our hostel gate to be picked up by World Vision (a child sponsorship organization). I've been sponsoring a now-12-year-old girl named Beiba for years, practicing my spanish through letters with her. We figured that while in Bolivia we might as well stop by to visit her and see World Vision at work. We were just expecting to meet Beiba and to talk to the local employees about the programs and their effectiveness. So when we arrived in Colomi to a room full of staff and kids, Beiba's entire family (parents, brother, and sister), and a breakfast buffet, we were very surprised (and slightly embarassed). The kids put on a play for us, and then we made our way to some rehab facilities World Vision started in Candelaria: Beiba's town. There was a mental and physical rehabilitation center. The two have since been intentionally passed off to the Bolivian government, but are still monitored by World Vision to make sure supplies and staff needs are heard. It was encouraging to see World Vision know when to step up, and when to step down and hand over ownership and awareness to the local government. Then we made a half hour drive to Beiba's community. The tour started with lunch overlooking the lake and a fish farm. After stuffing ourselves with fish and rice, we went to the primary school in the area. Here some of the school kids took up full-sized USA and Bolivia flags and led us in a parade down a dirt road to their school. We played parachute games, watched choreographed songs and dances, and got to know eachother. Beiba started opening up, telling me about the delicious ducks on the water and reciting the dates of my birthday and wedding anniversary, which she had memorized. From there we walked to Beiba's house, which was right near the beautiful lake. Her dad owned farm land up the hill, and Beiba took great pride showing me every flower and vegetable in their home garden. Her dad had gone fishing on the lake the night before, and her mom served up the piping hot fried fish with rice and vegetables. I'm not a fish person, but this was legitimately delicious. After a pleasant meal, we passed out presents (Beiba's birthday was that coming Saturday), and said our goodbyes and thank-yous. Beiba made me a neon pink and purple scarf that took her 2 weeks. So sweet. As we were leaving we stopped on the side of the road to learn how local &quot;chips&quot; are made (by stomping on them and leaving them outside in the frost). These chips can be saved for years before re-hydrating and cooking. As the day ended, we headed back to the Colomi World Vision office for a birthday celebration, copious amounts of sugar, and a couple local gifts from the organization to us. I was extremely impressed by the dedication of the staff. All were local and friendly, most commuted over an hour, and all believed in the work they were doing. Our main guide for the day, Sophia, explained that there were no other children aid programs that she knew of in Bolivia, but that World Vision supports 42 villages, with emphasis on community development projects. All the kids we saw in the play earlier were part of World Vision &quot;scouts&quot;, where kids learn about God, their rights as citizens, hygiene, and proper treatment of people. Three thousand out of eleven thousand children in Beiba's area are sponsored. Throughout our travels I have become wary of locals seeing the west as the &quot;white rich people&quot; with bottomless pockets and all the answers. I see local leadership and empowerment from within the community as healthier and more effective means of development. But there is also something to be said for giving kids a kick-start in life and letting them know someone across the world believes in them. No system is perfect, but Mark and I believe World Vision uses their money well and wholeheartedly. The next day we went to the Jesus statue of Cochabamba, which is bigger than the one in Rio. Also less crowded and more pleasant. Later we (finally) finished our tourist shopping in town. That night and the next day were spent at our hostel chatting with a German girl and a British couple (who just became great-grandparents) that have been traveling for 10 years. That's right. 10 YEARS. I can't even imagine.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b8057f80c44f44d5a042f960dd4ddb69~mv2.jpg"/><div>Waiting for Lunch to be Made</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b4a0b98f59f944429075b0701c81fa41~mv2.jpg"/><div>A Little Bit of Drama</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a69c3ddb46b1435b9a2076335e995ce5~mv2.jpg"/><div>Songs at the World Vision Colomi Office</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a87244c330d54828990d73d048a1d083~mv2.jpg"/><div>Taking a Bow</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3333bd1288eb4dbeb93b404710069aef~mv2.jpg"/><div>Parade of Flags</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6344d3aa3c41407e99de2fe0c119e844~mv2.jpg"/><div>&quot;Welcome to Bolivia&quot;</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2645d7a42c0c486e8d64acd61616bcb7~mv2.jpg"/><div>Cat and Mouse</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_45f96ce6badd4a76bb7d8090db750777~mv2.jpg"/><div>Attack!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f1a5107d30624f0496763223f842db44~mv2.jpg"/><div>Parachute Fun</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_47d409c01084446a943219bb699bc798~mv2.jpg"/><div>Over There, Mark!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_29a6daff8a8a4511b67d06ddd5ce255c~mv2.jpg"/><div>Football, of Course</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_75928b755b224582b4bf5af21e768dba~mv2.jpg"/><div>Time for a Dance</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_507449520c9d4e4882802f5148caf151~mv2.jpg"/><div>Picture Time</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ec7420d346934d8b8af095b8829627e4~mv2.jpg"/><div>Really High 5</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4d1a7738067e4003936204a3c8595a02~mv2.jpg"/><div>Beiba's House</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_09b801dba0584cf281cbd70d85ffbb7f~mv2.jpg"/><div>Showing me the Garden</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8243eaac93d04ca6be92fdc29986e840~mv2.jpg"/><div>Looking for Fish</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7bb066ffb39143e5a9f62512d3be94d4~mv2.jpg"/><div>She Made me a Scarf.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_150b6e15d8fa4d2c8dbbebdaeb2de99a~mv2.jpg"/><div>After a Fresh-Caught Meal</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_826f2c27091b41059dd40323bfec4c42~mv2.jpg"/><div>Stomping Potatoes</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sucre...For Real This Time - Sucre, Bolivia</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Back in the relative warmth in Sucre, we decided to relax for three days. But Mark and I are terrible at relaxing. This whole trip we haven't stayed anywhere for more than a week. Our three days were filled with blogging, doing overdue chores, buying airline tickets for Mexico, and bus tickets our next stop, Cochabamba. We don't really feel relaxed, but it was still nice to be in one place for more than a day or two. The city is beautiful. Also, our terrace rooftop hostel included a kitchen,
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/12/SucreFor-Real-This-Time---Sucre-Bolivia
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/12/SucreFor-Real-This-Time---Sucre-Bolivia
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 18:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Back in the relative warmth in Sucre, we decided to relax for three days. But Mark and I are terrible at relaxing. This whole trip we haven't stayed anywhere for more than a week. Our three days were filled with blogging, doing overdue chores, buying airline tickets for Mexico, and bus tickets our next stop, Cochabamba. We don't really feel relaxed, but it was still nice to be in one place for more than a day or two. The city is beautiful. Also, our terrace rooftop hostel included a kitchen, cable TV (almost exclusively in Spanish), and wifi. Great place to hunker down before our next move to Cochabamba! Sorry no pictures. This was &quot;relaxing&quot; time.</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uyuni - Uyuni, Bolivia</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
After a bus, taxi, and another bus, we arrived in freezing Uyuni (literally, below 32 degrees) just after 1 AM. We wandered the ghost town until we found an open hotel with a triple room. Done. Our tour started at 10 AM the next morning. We ate breakfast and stuffed ourselves into the Toyota 4Runner that would be our home for the next three days. We shared the car with our guide, Marine, two Danish guys, and two Swiss guys. Sitting in the middle of the car, surrounded by big men, I felt very<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6c31f29453cc4ef691aee9610777f89f%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/09/Uyuni---Uyuni-Bolivia
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/09/Uyuni---Uyuni-Bolivia
</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>After a bus, taxi, and another bus, we arrived in freezing Uyuni (literally, below 32 degrees) just after 1 AM. We wandered the ghost town until we found an open hotel with a triple room. Done. Our tour started at 10 AM the next morning. We ate breakfast and stuffed ourselves into the Toyota 4Runner that would be our home for the next three days. We shared the car with our guide, Marine, two Danish guys, and two Swiss guys. Sitting in the middle of the car, surrounded by big men, I felt very safe. It's hard to describe how pretty the landscape was. I'll try, but recommend seeing the photos to get a better idea of our tour. The first day included a visit to the train graveyard, a dust field full of trains from waaaay back in the day, and the famous Salina de Uyuni, an ancient ocean that dried up and left behind TONS of salt on a giant flat plain. In the middle, rising up from all the flat salt, was Cactus Island - a green oasis of cactus. Really cool. That night we stayed in a small salt hotel. Literally, it was made of salt. The outside was...underwhelming, but the inside beautiful. Unfortunately a couple of German girls and English guys didn't realize sound travels through salt. And there were some rowdy Israelis who hot-boxed the place with cigarettes. We were happy to leave the next day. Day 2 was lagoon day. We saw four lakes of &quot;different colors&quot;. They weren't necessarily vibrant rainbow colors, but they sure were really nice to look at. We also saw amazing mountains, volcanos, the border of Chile, flamingos, a rock that looks like a big tree, and lots of llamas. Our next hotel was really cold and simple, but offered yogurt, cereal, AND pancakes for breakfast. Oh, yumm! The last day featured fast driving (to the point of super scary), geysers, natural hot springs, a green lagoon, and a flat tire. It was SO cold that we were using our sleeping bag as a blanket in the car (the cars heater was broken). Seven hour of driving later, we made it to peaceful Uyuni in time to watch Brazil get destroyed by Germany 7-1 in the World Cup. We bought a bus ticket for the next day and checked into the same hotel for a lukewarm shower and some much-needed sleep.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6c31f29453cc4ef691aee9610777f89f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0d02c9a20f6f4a95aca8fab400771231~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3929c7a6b92f44949c2960866c18b382~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_39679f50706c4c0f80559110041e26fb~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_adb625e15d4b4e1a812705bef66f5cbc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_82911ddcf9e245338ad992d021578c8f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_22a6ebc5189040a1be948c4511e4a037~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_eee1fa6597094f98b0f245dd81f87cb7~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2b195a047f5849d9824f5ca96b3b4366~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5ff488454e974d99919ad20b9fca7721~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a5fa0233f5c347e8a77149174ffe4cce~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_bb8435cc14f14b8192ae5ad5a135a6da~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_593ce2357f884ca78318c622bc8e35df~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c8eefdaa1fea41b1a335917f2bac5177~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a726c6eddcd24f4a951cd672ecf66988~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_85a63b1bde5c46a1b32d208024e6a493~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_222a5df6e4cc43a8a726ce003aa0fd78~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_367af409cba3401bbbd600c9a40f400f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_426e4722eaaf456b96e3ab46bf15bc8d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b64bf7f76fff481593204eb077800685~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sucre - Sucre, Bolivia</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
After a night of sleep on the bus we popped into Sucre. A super relaxing (and warm) town that used to Bolivia's capital. We grabbed a taxi with our new Polish friends and ended up and some mom and pop hostel that looked pretty nice. But little did we know the horrors to come... We settled in, took a shower and went out to watch a FIFA game. After the game, we went back to our hostel to take a nap as it was the 4th of July and we had plans to bon fire later that evening with another American we<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_70db93f8442846f8abff53a405e8d0c6%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/05/Sucre---Sucre-Bolivia
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/05/Sucre---Sucre-Bolivia
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 18:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>After a night of sleep on the bus we popped into Sucre. A super relaxing (and warm) town that used to Bolivia's capital. We grabbed a taxi with our new Polish friends and ended up and some mom and pop hostel that looked pretty nice. But little did we know the horrors to come... We settled in, took a shower and went out to watch a FIFA game. After the game, we went back to our hostel to take a nap as it was the 4th of July and we had plans to bon fire later that evening with another American we met. An hour or so went by and then I woke up scratching. You guessed it! BED BUGS AGIAN! That makes our 7th encounter with the devils in under a year. Immediately, we went through our cleaning drill and switched rooms. So much for the 4th. The bugs took the party out of us. The next day we decided to completely move hostels because the staff was giving us a hard time about the bugs (and didn't believe us). Then we cruised around town, visited a ginormous cemetery, and checked out tours to Uyuni: the popular tourist thing to do in Bolivia (see next post). However, their have been lots of blockades recently making it a tough place to get to. Most places said we wouldn't be able to go for weeks. But then one lady told us we could go, but we would have to go now (before the blockades started again). STRESS TIME! Cancel our hostel booking, pack our bags, buy the last two seats on a bus to Potosi, and catch a late night bus to Uyuni from there. It's times like these that we are grateful that we only have one backpack to pack and carry :-)</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_70db93f8442846f8abff53a405e8d0c6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_60f44fff05384c3bae41a8dba7cc13e9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_fa3b924df64d4a80bc66da7fbbd99c0e~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Copacabana, Isla del Sol - Isla del Sol , Bolivia</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
The journey to Copacabana included a bus ride, a ferry, and another bus ride. We arrived in Copacabana and found ourselves in a beautiful hotel room on the edge of Lake Titicaca. Absolutely beautiful. We found a bar to watch the USA game (with a room full of Belgians and Bolivians), and were disappointed by the result (Belgium won). Luckily the loss was padded by friendly Belgian trash talk, and a pity drink from the Bolivians. The next morning we took a ferry to Isla del Sol. The "thing to do"<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_06fce44012c7459c861cb836b8c0cb94%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/03/Copacabana-Isla-del-Sol---Isla-del-Sol-Bolivia
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/03/Copacabana-Isla-del-Sol---Isla-del-Sol-Bolivia
</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>The journey to Copacabana included a bus ride, a ferry, and another bus ride. We arrived in Copacabana and found ourselves in a beautiful hotel room on the edge of Lake Titicaca. Absolutely beautiful. We found a bar to watch the USA game (with a room full of Belgians and Bolivians), and were disappointed by the result (Belgium won). Luckily the loss was padded by friendly Belgian trash talk, and a pity drink from the Bolivians. The next morning we took a ferry to Isla del Sol. The &quot;thing to do&quot; is hike the island from North to South. The views are incredible, the stone ruins cool, the water crystal clear, and the sun scorching. Thankfully we were forewarned and came prepared with sunglasses and sunscreen. We met a friendly Germany guy who shared a pizza with us at a restaurant with an absolutely unbelievable location overlooking the water. His ear was black and bloody, having been bitten by a monkey at the monkey sanctuary he was staying at. This further justifies my fear of monkeys. Safely arriving at the South end of the island three hours later, we checked into a hostel, sharing a room with a nice French couple. We spent the evening walking to the water (which meant a giant climb uphill to our place), and chatting with a hippy Polish couple, who would prove to be recurring friends on our trip. The next day was a big travel day. 2 hour ferry, then a 3 hour bus to La Paz, then an overnight bus to Sucre (we wanted to go to Uyuni, but the road was closed due to strikes - the people want a bus terminal). Exhausted, we shared a taxi in Sucre with our new Polish friends and counted in our heads the number of bus rides left in our future.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_06fce44012c7459c861cb836b8c0cb94~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1d40f4d470974dcd8316ac18bb55ef11~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c8589586618544d39de224dd82b7a548~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3fa6a4e4481547e99fcd6861aca694dc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2e12c80601794eb79f70b1cbeda8657b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_177f4d72b5cd4c48a800991b48fa07c2~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ea4143da87544f9fa83e3c80f8b0ecb4~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_50a84781939e4842935183b6fe048f8c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_639273f5d4b14347b04c7270fae38a89~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_74e8e718d5bd4096af9cfb63e30128de~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_999bb3ae65bb45639464c8927a16df23~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7b39288e555743ba8f5f2c63e09a0f53~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b2fe271330094ceb847436491adf3d53~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_05e3902ac349459dad68deedf395d999~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9aa93a6d7ca848ffb7caca1de8d283df~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1463fdaf59b44892b797301155543d4d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dd7e0e4560814f1a89cdb41dcde6bd01~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_16dbab398f5f44029f6a7beb2a05a100~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2ed5021561034b30adf7a2a86c2ee4fc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d618354f50f6410390f9b562e958abfb~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>La Paz - La Paz, Bolivia</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We had done some quick research on Bolivian immigration. Every blog said America is one of the only countries that has to pay, and if you are flying into La Paz you need to bring the fee in US dollars and they will let you in. Unfortunately we were made to go through immigration in Cochabamba (during our layover). They asked for the money, a copy of our credit card, our flight out of the country, hostel reservation, invitation into Bolivia, and also our vaccination records. This was the second<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6dfd03ba5c5b4ac1af94eb4ad14dc752%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/01/La-Paz---La-Paz-Bolivia
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/07/01/La-Paz---La-Paz-Bolivia
</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 18:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We had done some quick research on Bolivian immigration. Every blog said America is one of the only countries that has to pay, and if you are flying into La Paz you need to bring the fee in US dollars and they will let you in. Unfortunately we were made to go through immigration in Cochabamba (during our layover). They asked for the money, a copy of our credit card, our flight out of the country, hostel reservation, invitation into Bolivia, and also our vaccination records. This was the second worst immigration experience we've ever had (after India). Thankfully an airport worker had us e-mail her the information over the snail-slow internet, and printed the pages. The immigration man didn't even look at the papers, just found our name on each page and let us through. As a result, we missed our original fight but thankfully we were able to catch the last flight of the night to La Paz! We arrived in La Paz and took a shared taxi with a friendly local archaeologist and another local (airport taxis are all shared). The city is built in a valley with crazy hills soaring up on the sides. Everything you can see is covered in earth-colored buildings. It's really, REALLY big. We made our way to our hostel, settled in, and conked out. The internet at our original hostel didn't work, so the next morning we changed places and walked around town until our 4:30 PM main event of the day: Cholitas Wrestling! &quot;Cholitas&quot; is the correct name for the indigenous women who live in Bolivia. They all wear poofy skirts (to look bigger), sweaters, and tiny bowler hats. Cholitas wrestling is basically WWF (fake fighting), but with middle-aged men in spandex costumes and Cholitas women fighters. The event takes place in neighboring El Alto, on top of the La Paz hill, in a tiny gym with a fighting ring. The audience is half Bolivian, half tourist. Highlights included the audience throwing popcorn and water at the &quot;bad guys'&quot;, a wrestler being thrown onto three tourists in the audience, and a man back-flipping from the top of the ring onto his opponent on the cement below. We were laughing really hard. See the below photos for some visuals. After all the excitement, we found some street burgers to enjoy with the free nightly beer from our hostel and an over-due game of fooseball. The next morning we enjoyed the other perk of our new hostel: an all you can eat pancake breakfast! After stuffing ourselves, we walked to the main plaza for a free city walking tour. We had it in our heads that walking tours are generally lame, but (besides the crazy NY man who tries to get tips for information about the jail he just got out of), this tour was awesome. The two women leading it were hilarious and full of fun facts. We learned why the local women wear tiny bowler hats: years ago the men in Bolivia ordered bowler hats from Europe. Europe figured their heads would be tiny since the men are short. When the tiny hats arrived the men tricked the women into buying them as the &quot;newest feminine fashion in Europe&quot;. They're up to $750 each and still bought and worn today. You can tell if a woman is single or taken by how she wears the hat. The women here also wear layers and layers of skirts to look bigger. They do all the work, and men find the bigger women more attractive. To seduce the men, they lift their skirts to show their calves. On the tour we also learned about a witch street that sells llama fetuses. Whenever a new building is made a fetus is purchased to bring good luck on the structure. A couple generations ago when really big buildings were being created, a witch doctor would be hired to send his men to find a homeless person that would not be missed. They would then give him booze until he passed out, and bury him alive in the foundation of the new structure. Thankfully this no longer happens, but bodies are occasionally found when tearing down old buildings. OK sorry - enough of random facts...you can go on the tour or talk to us for more. The next morning we boarded another bus - this one bound for Copacabana (a different Copacabana from Brazil) and the Isla Del Sol.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6dfd03ba5c5b4ac1af94eb4ad14dc752~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_52c3cb11f9a5419ca4fb3ec035fbb321~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_aaf221d5300b455f8261b93bf8579729~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_844f7d0952ef47ccb840890138076019~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b531eb69cd874fd2b37617caafc28a88~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_aebb5964a6d24fa28735fe240a16f8d6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a3fd46a9e4d849548fdf8a2136576fed~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c4fb4eb53f924dd4bfff8021c9d9e9ae~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8e4739c2ce9e435c80ec2897de0a8d47~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3e701f7e6f8f4afc9ff6f8f6bc846d0a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e14bdf16bf1443beb9516422211ecd8f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_235b69270bd9492c86d503ad3cced994~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_69696f7c4c544abcb5114bf6aed5f6cd~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_13af727626b94a45aa94f7a537f342a4~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_41503121bf0a490ea6b5c3ee594e7fe2~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_da2d430fca5444b3a6caf8af196bab19~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7a61b1428fd349fb8f3948700c91a434~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1eed9fb0097f4154b6011c8c7eea55a5~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ac671c81a25141e9b18b2eb3f0040e2f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7b97c528ab114d2399f6d3d172d0750a~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>São Paulo - São Paulo, Brazil</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We rolled into Sao Paolo at 7 AM on an overnight bus from Rio. It is really big. As in one of the biggest cities in the world. After a few subways during rush hour and a walk through some quirky street art, we reached Pat's apartment in the Vila Madalena neighborhood. Pat is a generous soul who volunteered to host us for a few nights. We know his brother, Ricardo, from Colorado. He is a brother in the Catholic Church who helps to organize volunteer trips to South America. I've done one trip, and<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_07e7a84059fb49c696047e8ce3f21169%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/27/S%C3%A3o-Paulo---S%C3%A3o-Paulo-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/27/S%C3%A3o-Paulo---S%C3%A3o-Paulo-Brazil
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 18:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We rolled into Sao Paolo at 7 AM on an overnight bus from Rio. It is really big. As in one of the biggest cities in the world. After a few subways during rush hour and a walk through some quirky street art, we reached Pat's apartment in the Vila Madalena neighborhood. Pat is a generous soul who volunteered to host us for a few nights. We know his brother, Ricardo, from Colorado. He is a brother in the Catholic Church who helps to organize volunteer trips to South America. I've done one trip, and Mark has done two. We found the key under his mat, opened the door, and our jaws dropped. It was beautiful. His bachelor apartment was big, clean, chic, and had an amazing view of the city. We took a shower, found our bed (in our private room), and fell asleep until 2:00 PM. We got up the energy to go to a crazy coffee place in his neighborhood. You can choose your coffee from an enormous list, choose how you want it brewed, and they bring all the supplies to your table to brew in front of you. Crazy. Back at the house, we met Pat and had some wine on the porch. His parents had invited the three of us to their place for dinner, so that was our next stop. Pat's parents live walking distance away in a breathtaking apartment building. From their apartment (which is a whole floor) you can see far into the distance. Sao Paolo is so big that all you could see was city with no end. His mom prepared us delicious seafood curry and a delicious passion fruit/condensed milk/gelatin desert that I want to try my hand at when we get home. Pat's dad, American, told us all about their lives and travels. The next morning our friend Kate, who we went to Peru with five years ago, picked us up to explore. She is an artist who has been living outside the city for three months, and teaches english in Sao Paolo a few times a week. We first went to the USA vs. Germany game at a packed bar down the street. America lost, but still made it to the next round! After the game we went to grab street hamburgers and walk to an art exhibition. This extremely famous Japanese woman who lives in an asylum and is obsessed with polka-dots was offering a free look at her latest art, which was...unique. We enjoyed it. That night I made a prochutto/squash/spinach/gnochi dish that was absolutely delicious. Score one for me! Afterward our tired caught up to us again - we watched a new movie about a true story of US special forces in Afghanistan. It was excellent but a little intense for me. So we watched Mythbusters afterward. Our last day in Sao Paolo started with lunch out with Pat in the business district. Then we walked around and received an official tour of the area (including a chaotic market) with Kate and him. Mark made delicious chicken with beans and rice for dinner, and then it was time to party. Pat had turned 30 the week before while on vacation, so he decided to throw a big party to celebrate. It was a grown-up party, complete with food and a full bar. We bought crazy chestnut-like things to roast as a snack that were surprisingly delicious. We were awake until everyone left at 4 AM (people stay up late in Brazil), and got up at 7 AM to make our way to the airport before the city went to a standstill for the Brazil soccer game.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0069d99fb7974b05abc08b7f99c1927f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_de22a147b5344de7b2081a1947299fd7~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9393d9f601e046f1aa4b81410134f2c6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_10bfc553883746c8a49f2e44944bdfa6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ae86898e7832498e90cd2d17c5db15af~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ee43ee694ba4433dab64f00ae8e37e92~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f20edf97e22e48779d1e9b0df22a4106~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_00cd6a8372cf482db94bb55bb39c68d5~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_07e7a84059fb49c696047e8ce3f21169~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ae8af6348d614e1b9058cd429855308e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_38a1b41916d442c58562e81e0da8428e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0f19c4fe8ca549308309ad107fb93976~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_659b1403d4d3475a8e5a5f0ad4ec1341~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rio - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We were picked up in Rio by our Airbnb host, Jefferson. I can't remember if we've talked about Airbnb. It's basically Couchsurfing, but you pay for it. Showing up in Rio during the World Cup (where one dorm bed in a hostel is $90/night/pp) made us look for alternative lodging options. We shared Jefferson and his wife's (Nina) bedroom along with their dog (Scott) and two cats (Cheetah and John). A little tight, but they were super nice, showed us the city, and we got a good price downtown.<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8926297274634c56a498a8b55f10d2b2%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/24/Rio---Rio-de-Janeiro-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/24/Rio---Rio-de-Janeiro-Brazil
</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We were picked up in Rio by our Airbnb host, Jefferson. I can't remember if we've talked about Airbnb. It's basically Couchsurfing, but you pay for it. Showing up in Rio during the World Cup (where one dorm bed in a hostel is $90/night/pp) made us look for alternative lodging options. We shared Jefferson and his wife's (Nina) bedroom along with their dog (Scott) and two cats (Cheetah and John). A little tight, but they were super nice, showed us the city, and we got a good price downtown. Shortly after we arrived, Jefferson and Nina took us to an all you can eat pizza joint with a few of their friends. I think it was the first time we've seen &quot;All You Can Eat&quot; since we left the states. We stuffed our faces, even though the pizza was more like cheese bread. Most restaurants in Brazil are a buffet and charge you by weight. We didn't realize this when we first arrived from Argentina, and definitely paid a hefty price at our first bus rest stop. Most of their friends are into Muay Thai, and were trying to get me to come train. I told them maybe... The area we were in is called Lapa, which is where most of the night life happens. At night, the streets become so full of people that the police often have to close the roads so nobody gets run over. Street stands get up all over the place selling greasy hotdogs (with raisins), and of course a wide selection of alcoholic beverages. There are no open container tickets, so the entire district of Lapa basically becomes a giant bar/urinal/grease stand. Surprisingly it's actually pretty fun to walk through. Musicians play samba in the streets, often battling each other like a drumline. On our second night a friend from grad-school, Porter, met us. He was also touring Brazil with a couple of his friends. While we were eating, a bunch of people protesting FIFA came marching down the street. Some of the Brazilians are against hosting the World Cup because they think the money could have been better spent elsewhere (which is probably true). Either way, they came marching down the streets with their signs saying F*** FIFA. Right behind them was an excessively large police force (including a helicopter) making sure everything stayed peaceful. We're not sure things remained peaceful because we definitely caught whiffs of tear gas while we were finishing our meal. The next day Jefferson took us on a tour around the city. We saw some of the major government buildings, and one of the craziest churches we've ever seen. The entire thing is built out of concrete. Laura thinks it's ugly. I think it's pretty cool looking. At night, we went to see Jefferson's friend from England, Deepak, rap at a local hostal bar. Yes, Deepak is his real name. Not his rapper name. He can drop the beats! In an English accent even... The following day Laura and I checked out Sugarloaf: a &quot;mountain&quot; that overlooks the city of Rio from the ocean. Most people take a gondola to the top but Jefferson told us that you can hike half way up, so we opted for the hike to build character. He accompanied us along the slippery trail which took out quite a few tourists. But it was all worth it when we saw the views at the top. You can see the ocean and Rio with the Christ the Redeemer statue looking over the city. Pretty epic. After Sugarloaf we went straight to Copacabana beach for &quot;FIFA Fun Fest&quot; where they would play the USA - Portugal game. FIFA Fun Fest is basically a giant party on the beach with a huge TV to watch the games. Porter and his friends met us and brought some extra USA face paint for us to sport. The US had officially taken over the beach, outnumbering Portuguese fans 10:1. All of you should know the result of the game (the US was up 2-1, but Portugal scored in the last minute to tie). By the end of the game, I lost my voice and the beach was quiet. We were in shock. Still had a great time, especially talking smack to the Portugese, and booing Ronaldo every time he was on TV. Hotdogs were waiting for us back at the apartment. The next day we opted for another hike. This time to the Christ the Redeemer statue that overlooks Rio. The trail starts in a botanical gardens and works its way through the forest up to the mountain where the statue stands. It's absolutely gorgeous, but STEEP. At one point we were literally rock climbing, holding on to a chain that was bolted into the rock. Underneath us were Brazilian police watching us. Probably ready to take tourists to the hospital if they fell. Once we finally made it to the top, we were turned around because we were told we had to buy tickets down below (the opposite of what was posted on their website). Buzz kill! So after 2 hours of a grueling hike, we had to take a bus back down to buy a ticket and then bus back up. Lame. The statue was also packed with tourists from the World Cup. You could barely lift up your hands to take a picture. But just like the Sugarloaf hike, it was worth it in the end. The statue is huge and the views of the city are superb. While we were there a guy was working on Jesus' finger. Apparently it got hit by lightning. After hiking back down, we were able to catch the second half of the Brazil - Mexico game at our hosts apartment. They had popcorn and juice waiting for us. We devoured the snacks as we had eaten nothing after the hike. Deepak was also there and suggested we go out for &quot;all you can eat&quot; pizza again. Laura and I quickly agreed. 20 cheesy pizza slices and a stomach ache later, we hit the sack. Exhausted. Our last day in Rio was a beach day. Ipanima beach and Copacabana. Tourists and locals alike litter these giant beaches playing soccer, drinking beer, and soaking up the sun. We rented bikes and cruised around the city people watching. The whole world has packed itself onto these beaches for the World Cup, so you definitely stay entertained. As the sun went down we biked home to catch a city bus to the regional bus station where we would catch a ride to São Paulo. We bid farewell to our awesome Airbnb hosts and caught a bus to the bus station. By the way, the bus drivers in Rio are absolutely nuts. If you've ever seen the movie: SPEED, that's what it felt like. I'm pretty sure we took a few u-turns at 30+ mph. Not kidding.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8926297274634c56a498a8b55f10d2b2~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5952c6fe2db64e7f9bab19882a432cc6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2a5628e2fdf2467f928ab7b64b5296e9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_16019ea5103349ee89a05133550d3f55~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_97fa99dc1b8c41498d7a14672cf5a48d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_cee891fd3b744ab5b9eb45b9ea2281ca~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_bcbad6ba182e414d90542eac61401992~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_91b687984689481c9bf7dd123a6cc481~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_650a8e1dd89240bba1a0b9677d559d29~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8754b23c132447b4ab961fb71b102d01~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a6a2608deb204017947aa208ab4c1e2a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3fd302e48c53419d8a91015b38feacbd~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3c1354cee57f4954b844b1473e3acd5d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dfdceb07a73a40c7ab620595aa63f753~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_95c7b501d51f49d8ac2e7504e3c40b18~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f843c0a4805b4334b6202f7b10be5964~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8b5e7b5e2aa04abcab11ed2bb0519807~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f3c2469531724bc599698d0957fda151~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dd9a2113c1c04b53b0e54164c7f3ea38~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ed9aa41acfff46fea5b5043b7c00f0b3~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_534eb6d0a14f4d1f807155dae70bb5b7~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2ef2c31864cb49e4acfb26dcdb61930a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4ace1b8907464e7bbb4cb88052db7312~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8d46677a5d2d4659b0fb5f9064b64c28~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6536a569240342eea9dae2ed073ac79f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a134da7ef0034b7db73fc049db7473d5~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7ffb8ad7afb54360a1a57b9189884523~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a9a25ed877774abea7d78404a0700314~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4a20f83f4a824587a4b0015cb0606b12~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d50e8c9eee224f8cbca5105fd1f2045c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b780c11316e94829aa7ccf58984839ce~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3d459f6c226f46668bcde5bba28ba265~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_21e452e6cd9f487eb879bba58d907605~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ouro Preto: "Gold Black" - Ouro Preto, Brazil</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We were met at the Ouro Preto bus station by Breno and his friend Paul. We would be couch surfing at their fraternity for the night. "Fraternity" conjures images of keg parties and a trashed house, but in Ouro Preto they are more of a big house for friends to live together. We were greeted by friendly roommates, and our own bed. Awesome. Thankfully everyone in Breno's house spoke Spanish or English, so we got by fine. Breno showed us the local university, and also took us for a walk through the<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b25ab2c1b86c49199cac5a300f5ba090%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/19/Ouro-Preto-Gold-Black---Ouro-Preto-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/19/Ouro-Preto-Gold-Black---Ouro-Preto-Brazil
</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 18:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We were met at the Ouro Preto bus station by Breno and his friend Paul. We would be couch surfing at their fraternity for the night. &quot;Fraternity&quot; conjures images of keg parties and a trashed house, but in Ouro Preto they are more of a big house for friends to live together. We were greeted by friendly roommates, and our own bed. Awesome. Thankfully everyone in Breno's house spoke Spanish or English, so we got by fine. Breno showed us the local university, and also took us for a walk through the beautiful old downtown. We visited a church with an inside completely covered in gold - the second most &quot;golded&quot; church in Brazil. The hills covered in beautiful buildings made us feel like we were in a mini-utopia. Toward the end of our walk we were stopped by three middle-aged women in the town square. They had had a few beers, and asked to take a photo with us. They then proceeded to tell us how beautiful we are and how cute our accents are. They gave us their phone numbers and invited us to stay with them and their families an hour outside the city. Breno couldn't stop laughing. That night we made shokshooka (an Israeli egg dish) for the house, and Breno made us his famous caparinas (a Brazilian drink similar to a margarita). A couple of his roommates had studied english but never had the opportunity to speak to native english speakers. They really enjoyed telling us stories and practicing. It was a lot of fun hanging out on their back porch overlooking the city. We took the local city bus to the bus station the next morning to catch our ride to Rio. Unfortunately a few minutes into the ride we were stopped due to a parade. It turns out that these celebrations happen often. After waiting 15 minutes we decided to ditch the bus and go to the station on foot so we wouldn't miss our bus. Unfortunately this meant a mile-long run up big cobblestone hills filled with celebration preparations. Not ideal. We made it minutes before the bus left, purchasing the last two tickets.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b25ab2c1b86c49199cac5a300f5ba090~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_53e46012586d4b2c81bf3fb31043771a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_11a6112a220a415e877bcbce71442adc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_26233f016f4e4e029a2ea193ae3cd6ba~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6de6b9684ba64df698d306c57687352a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_303dacfbeb744aff85b5a19697217766~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_cdd448d4e20c432ba832eba2edfcd13f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ddb7c2b74fb9493fbb3eb88e2feb2628~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4df8361e6dc14901bd6441cd01e63a74~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b740af50ad5f47aba2d8981a749c70e3~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_eed72068636243c297499561e619b81a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_bf30c6cac27c48719b4a8c732c845782~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7936be59a77640438661b8824b5e524f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_723ee56ad69f4a4a8141e343713f3426~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e93a17eb887e4b57902abd53a2b590f6~mv2_d_1280_1280_s_2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Belo Horizonte - Belo Horizonte, Brazil</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
What do you get when you put an engineer, a lawyer, and a traveling married couple in a 3-bedroom apartment? Our time in Belo Horizonte! We arrived at Belo Horizonte at 9 PM after a wonderful (sarcasm) 31-hour bus ride. We asked the woman working information at the bus station if she could talk in spanish or english...the answer was "no". Turns out most Brazilians only speak portugese - the biggest language-barrier country we have found so far. We walked out of the station toward the subway,<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2089d88dc9b947c59a1f3c58b29edd3a%7Emv2_d_1280_1280_s_2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/18/Belo-Horizonte---Belo-Horizonte-Brazil
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/18/Belo-Horizonte---Belo-Horizonte-Brazil
</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>What do you get when you put an engineer, a lawyer, and a traveling married couple in a 3-bedroom apartment? Our time in Belo Horizonte! We arrived at Belo Horizonte at 9 PM after a wonderful (sarcasm) 31-hour bus ride. We asked the woman working information at the bus station if she could talk in spanish or english...the answer was &quot;no&quot;. Turns out most Brazilians only speak portugese - the biggest language-barrier country we have found so far. We walked out of the station toward the subway, quickly finding ourselves surrounded by transvestites, hourly hotels, and drunk people. Exhausted and sketched out, we gave in and got a taxi. The driver didn't speak English but was extremely nice; he even caught our overpayment mistake. We booked and Airbnb reservation (like Couch Surfing, but you pay) to stay with Mateus and his roommate Sergio near the university. Mateus only spoke Portugese (a rediculous mix of Spanish, French and Italian with a twist of Russian accent), but Sergio is fluent in English, which was excellent. We could communicate with Mateus by speaking Spanish, but the translation of Portugese back to Spanish could be a little rough. Thankfully they turned out to be amazingly friendly hosts with an apartment in a wonderful location. Sergio's sister was visiting the first night, so we all walked to &quot;FIFA Fan Fest&quot;, which has screenings of the soccer games, nightly live bands, an indoor amusement park ride, and plenty of scantily-clad Brazilians. We were in absolute shock after all the modest countries on our travels. I hadn't seen so much thigh since we were in the states. Then we ate delicious burritos. Day two we picked up our World Cup game tickets at a big mall downtown. This was perfect, because after having my bag stolen I was in need of clothes. Big time. Shopping successful, tickets in hand, we prepped for the big USA vs Ghana game. We met one of Sergio's friends at a bar downtown, and soon found a whole smattering of eager Americans glued to numerous TVs. WE WON!! Now I can't say that I watch any soccer, but I am extremely competitive, and something about the World Cup is consuming. I am completely into it. After the successful game we drove with Sergio to pick up &quot;Cha Cha&quot;, a 90 year old Indian/English/Brazilian man who is volunteering for the World Cup. He owns a store where Sergio went to university, and stays on Sergio's couch whenever he is in town for a night. The four of us drank chai tea, looked through Cha Cha's photo albums, and learned simple stretching and movement exercises that keep Cha Cha &quot;feeling young&quot;. Excellent man. By the time we waited in crazy traffic, hiked 1 mile from where the bus dropped us off, ran in a complete circle around the stadium, and finally found our seats, the Algeria - Belgium game was underway. It was absolutely amazing to be so close to the players, especially because they all look so tiny on TV. The team we finally decided as our favorite (Belgium) won, so we left celebrating. About half the people at the game were Brazilian. In the celebration one proposed his love to me, and another kissed my hand (under Mark's careful watch). Brazil played that night, so we went directly from the game to Sergio's friends' house to watch Brazil and fill up on delicious BBQ and homemade limeade. The celebration continued at Fifa Fan Fest, with live Samba music, dancing, and excellent people watching. The next morning Mateus drove us to the bus station to begin our journey southward.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2089d88dc9b947c59a1f3c58b29edd3a~mv2_d_1280_1280_s_2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_73088707b31f4bec91488d345f6ee9f0~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a49d3e3cc4d140848ee570be28aa8584~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_eeb7568be4d54847b46b9846f7653691~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c55e639f406b473da580e74f7f0ff600~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_487b1b7a81234d73a2b3764db8ff676b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_818223c7aa9247128ae515407ba6e70a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_db4339add1b34c8f8bc0933dfacda949~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_13f50b609147403385fe63684088ad7b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_38fb2cf6454f4c35aeccd07b8ae031ff~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_831aca3740af409bba62a345c6672579~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f8b2afe187904a3bae45987f88b8d715~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e92678bf8c7540dd9b317208ab471445~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_053d0437fd0d420e895a74865b93fc34~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_270bd6cbbbaa4d34860fac56697a9895~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>VIDEO: Part 3 of ?</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
What has ostriches, hummus, Indiana jones, and slip-n-slides? Travel video Part 3, of course! Copy and paste this into your browser to watch: http://youtu.be/9bjEfba6YBE Miss part 2? http://youtu.be/G2_a9STvLeU Miss part 1? http://youtu.be/1wEK9AXv56Q
]]>
</description>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/14/VIDEO-Part-3-of-
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/14/VIDEO-Part-3-of-
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 18:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>What has ostriches, hummus, Indiana jones, and slip-n-slides? Travel video Part 3, of course! Copy and paste this into your browser to watch: http://youtu.be/9bjEfba6YBE Miss part 2? http://youtu.be/G2_a9STvLeU Miss part 1? http://youtu.be/1wEK9AXv56Q</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iguazu Falls - Puerto Iguazu, Argentina</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We left Tilcara at 11am for... you guessed it... another bus ride! Little did we know that we wouldn't get to our destination, Iguazu Falls for 33 hours. Turns out we had to make four extra bus transfers than we wanted to, and when we finally got on our last bus, we were greeted with the knowledge that we would be going on a 7 hour detour. Turns out the Iguazu are had some serious flooding and the main road in and out was closed. But we could go around! IIt wasn't all bad. We used the time to<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a07f2c90da6048de8395adbc406b21fc%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/13/Iguazu-Falls---Puerto-Iguazu-Argentina
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/13/Iguazu-Falls---Puerto-Iguazu-Argentina
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We left Tilcara at 11am for... you guessed it... another bus ride! Little did we know that we wouldn't get to our destination, Iguazu Falls for 33 hours. Turns out we had to make four extra bus transfers than we wanted to, and when we finally got on our last bus, we were greeted with the knowledge that we would be going on a 7 hour detour. Turns out the Iguazu are had some serious flooding and the main road in and out was closed. But we could go around! IIt wasn't all bad. We used the time to make two new friends from Seattle: Seth and Tana. They have been touring all of South America by car and recently sold it, leaving them hostage to the same bus ride as us. Finally we arrived at in Iguazu at 8pm the day after leaving Tilcara. Seth and Tana had hostel reservations, and we were exhausted so we just latched on to them hoping we would get accommodation as well. Luckily the lady at the front desk told us that we could share a family size room. On the bus ride we had been telling them about our bed bug horror stories, so Seth sarcastically ripped off the covers of their bed to make sure they never suffer the same fate as us. Then he says, &quot;Mark, is this mold?&quot; I come over and take a look, &quot;BED BUGS!!!!!&quot; Not again! That makes 6 encounters with the (insert your choice of words here) for Laura and I in under a year. We quickly ran out of the hostel (luckily we hadn't paid yet), and went searching the streets for a place to sleep. Eventually we found a nice place where we could share a room. We cooked up some grub, swapped some more stories and hit the sack. The next morning we woke up early to check out one of the wonders of the new world: Iguazu Falls. Sorry Niagra, but this sight puts you to shame. Look at the pictures. The water was extra strong, brown from the mud, and part of the falls were closed due to the flooding. But we decided we liked being able to go during the flood because not many people get to see Iguazu that &quot;roaring&quot;. After the falls we parted ways with Seth and Tana as they were catching a flight to Natal, Brazil to watch the USA play in the World Cup. We decided to take a bus to Brazil instead. This wasn't the best decision. We just signed ourselves up for another 31 hour bus ride. 64 hours of bussing over 4 days....</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3d0dba9d02704ecaac2efe1e8d3e61d8~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_12c4ac30784347e4a99a8b9cd42b07dc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c36ff737c0be4f6185566953a6987c65~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_45a7246e479f4ae9a736c093c745f430~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a07f2c90da6048de8395adbc406b21fc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0ca3dd83fe20403d808f20f752f43bb4~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c09f05697ee24b1893c9fff2a3e02587~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1bade59e5da1407fb179d1303948cb43~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_134f0e89062e4ed69968c960187a0e8b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0b0b881f1c714a77852c69e561e130f1~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8722942654e44b679164a8fc48a88dfd~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_01aecc536a1a4f9db016d5530947ec59~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9cd4ac9fc54544e6b24d893113f2eb13~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a526d97fd7b849efaa2f93494c961589~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_afb1b4c889dc402b9af8626527c5c55c~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tilcara - Tilcara, Argentina</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
After our hike around Purmamarca, we took the next bus north and settled down in Tilcara. We were exhausted. After following a Colombian and Dutch guy to a hostel, we dropped off our things and explored town. It is small, full of dogs wearing felt blanket jackets, scattered with women in big hats, and very relaxed. The local culture is still well alive - and tourists are comparatively very few. I had a bad cold, so went to bed early. Mark woke me up around midnight. He had seen our archenemy: a<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d905b638872a44d2bb9926e7ed76c7a4%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/11/Tilcara---Tilcara-Argentina
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/11/Tilcara---Tilcara-Argentina
</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>After our hike around Purmamarca, we took the next bus north and settled down in Tilcara. We were exhausted. After following a Colombian and Dutch guy to a hostel, we dropped off our things and explored town. It is small, full of dogs wearing felt blanket jackets, scattered with women in big hats, and very relaxed. The local culture is still well alive - and tourists are comparatively very few. I had a bad cold, so went to bed early. Mark woke me up around midnight. He had seen our archenemy: a bedbug. Our fifth time with these unwanted visitors, we knew the drill: catch one, change rooms, shake out our clothes, and take another shower. Itchy and no fun. The next day I summoned my energy to make the uphill hike to Garganta de Dios (The Devil's Throat) Waterfall. It was an epically beautiful hike through desert, cacti, and crazy rock formations. After a couple hours we reached the downhill climb into a canyon. We hiked up the side of a very tiny river to the waterfall. Nice, but the hike to it was better. There we met our friend, &quot;Sam&quot;. Sam is a dog, and we shared our crackers with him. Mark fell in love. It turns out he, and other dogs in the area, follow hikers to and from town day in and day out. We had three friends join us for the hike back. At night we went to a restaurant on the plaza with delicious food and live folklore music. We tried llama for the first time, and ended our meal with a dulce de leche pancake. Absolutely delicious. The live entertainment was a middle-aged man with his guitar and the voice of an Argentinian folklore angel. We were hooked.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_81eec2d91d9545a0b1600cf811b2aa02~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_14d20a41eb6d4dbda0606ac303b9b4b7~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7f36c857e3164659b3f98e672a8e51df~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4c765c3d25654d8fa4bf2e6014ec8a26~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_555e3fd693154328a24d84963109f451~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8fbd812f3a654162b71de753bf82939e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_81cb5841aa794a4b9ed258f880e5b12f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_70689fb531f64d37a312a4f7f5b94c10~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d905b638872a44d2bb9926e7ed76c7a4~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f799c8754a5b4a28b7668bf0d48bed37~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purmamarca - Purmamarca, Argentina</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
On our way north we decided to get off the bus for a pit-stop in Pulmamarca. Our afternoon there was filled with the camino de los colorados, a hike through the desert showcasing the vibrant rock colors that the town is so famous for. There were hills covered in up to seven different kinds of rocks and colors - green, brown, red, yellow... After all the walking I stopped at a street BBQ vendor for the best empanada ever - full of ham and cheesy goodness. It was absolutely delicious. And enormous<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b33a6e48ab6042e6a4ed58032d6b1376%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/09/Purmamarca---Purmamarca-Argentina
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/09/Purmamarca---Purmamarca-Argentina
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 18:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>On our way north we decided to get off the bus for a pit-stop in Pulmamarca. Our afternoon there was filled with the camino de los colorados, a hike through the desert showcasing the vibrant rock colors that the town is so famous for. There were hills covered in up to seven different kinds of rocks and colors - green, brown, red, yellow... After all the walking I stopped at a street BBQ vendor for the best empanada ever - full of ham and cheesy goodness. It was absolutely delicious. And enormous - bigger than my hand!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a8aae16a22194a008cc8bd6b6037869e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ff3cd8ae9498470a83a75568d33107ca~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0ea896c74d5f452089fcf4ac5920122e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7ca08940bbf541c2869467ff10286621~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f5acbaed5c624d1dac4cce4345530ed6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dc20035ed104457b91072536647fc222~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b33a6e48ab6042e6a4ed58032d6b1376~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_14dc9bbfafbc4121aaf0b34f9f5156d5~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_12d269770d9646518325dcacf2bc33f6~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Salta - Salta, Argentina</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Even though it was another 24 hour bus ride, Salta was the perfect breath of fresh air after a rough last day in Buenos Aires. The large - but slow - town was just what the doctor ordered. It had large parks, a beautiful pink cathedral, a lively central plaza, and streets full of shops. Unfortunately I couldn't find one shirt I liked in all the stores, so I spent most of the time wearing clothes from Mark's bag. Our lack of excitement for the local wear was due to the plastering of cheesy<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3fa680a9c1774a1ea33fa7371dfdfdbf%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/08/Salta---Salta-Argentina
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/08/Salta---Salta-Argentina
</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Even though it was another 24 hour bus ride, Salta was the perfect breath of fresh air after a rough last day in Buenos Aires. The large - but slow - town was just what the doctor ordered. It had large parks, a beautiful pink cathedral, a lively central plaza, and streets full of shops. Unfortunately I couldn't find one shirt I liked in all the stores, so I spent most of the time wearing clothes from Mark's bag. Our lack of excitement for the local wear was due to the plastering of cheesy english sayings (&quot;you + me = happy&quot;) and plethora of turtle necks. Looks like re-stocking my clothes may be harder than expected!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3fa680a9c1774a1ea33fa7371dfdfdbf~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c964dc37613647ac9adf01d3725f3a8f~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>
City of Blood Sausage, Mate & a Stolen Backpack - Buenos Aires, Argentina
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
After our ridiculous flight path from South Africa -> Dubai -> Rio (lots of time for movie watching), we arrived in Buenos Aires, AKA the Europe of South America (think a shnazzy, expensive European city). Thankfully our good friend Carole connected us with her friend, Juan, who lives about 45 minutes outside downtown. After our first night in a hostel, Juan came to pick us up after work. He is our age, and lives with his sister (Agustina), and parents in a beautiful suburb of Buenos Aires.<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_cadf1f26036b49758fb0da32a44869cb%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/06/City-of-Blood-Sausage-Mate-a-Stolen-Backpack---Buenos-Aires-Argentina
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/06/City-of-Blood-Sausage-Mate-a-Stolen-Backpack---Buenos-Aires-Argentina
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>After our ridiculous flight path from South Africa -&gt; Dubai -&gt; Rio (lots of time for movie watching), we arrived in Buenos Aires, AKA the Europe of South America (think a shnazzy, expensive European city). Thankfully our good friend Carole connected us with her friend, Juan, who lives about 45 minutes outside downtown. After our first night in a hostel, Juan came to pick us up after work. He is our age, and lives with his sister (Agustina), and parents in a beautiful suburb of Buenos Aires. Their parents were on a Jamaican beach vacation, so it was just the four of us, Mango the dog, and the house help. We were greeted our first night by a delicious traditional dinner of milanesa (breaded and baked meat) and potatoes. The whole family came over - Juan, Augstina, her boyfriend, another sister, her husband, and their new daughter. It was delicious and a whole lot of fun. Breakfast was bread, dulce de leche (thick, creamy, melty, gooey caramel), and coffee. Turns out Argentinians are very similar to Spaniards - both speak crazy castellano spanish, have a five hour siesta in the middle of the day, eat dinky breakfasts, lunch at 2, snack at 6, and dinner at 10. That schedule definitely takes some getting used to. After eating, Agustina and her good friend Belen took us on a tour of the area. We saw the local cathedral, their country club and boat (Juan and his dad love sailing), and a nearby quirky river town (El Tigre). There we were given our first traditional Mate session. Mate is the local drink - highly caffeinated leaves mixed with small doses of hot water, drank with a special anti-clog straw, and passed in a circle. Our opinion went from bitterly overwhelming to mostly enjoyable. That night Juan invited his three travel friends over for a legitimate Argentinian BBQ. He cooked blood sausages (literally made of chunks of blood), regular sausages, and a huge slab of lomo meat. I tried a few times, but couldn't get past the fact that the blood sausages were literally-simply-blood. Mark loved them. I'm wondering if he is a vampire...? The next morning Juan dropped us at the Brazilian consulate on the way to work. Finally having all the required paperwork for a World Cup visa (bank statements, flight information, photos, application forms, hostel information...), we were set free to explore downtown Buenos Aires. We walked miles and miles, ending at the famous colorful buildings of &quot;El Caminito.&quot; We learned that almost no Argentinians dance salsa anymore, but the dance is kept alive for tourists in this area. It was really cool to watch - even if it is no longer a common cultural thing. After saying our goodbyes on Friday, we took the train into the city. We picked up our shiny new Brazilian visas, talked to a guy from New York for awhile, and went into Subway for a sandwich. That was our mistake. I was watching our big bags in the corner while Mark went to order. There was a problem with the receipt (food was double what it should have been), so we traded places so I could figure out what was wrong (I speak better Spanish). Mark was grabbing our drinks, eye on the bags, when I told him that they charged us for double meat and didn't give us the daily deal price. He said &quot;I didn't order double meat&quot;. I looked past him and immediately noticed that my bag was gone. I sprinted out the door and down the street, Mark going the other way, but the robber was gone. Seconds. I chatted with a cop (flashback to when we get held at knifepoint in Spain a few years ago), and made a police report. We are never going to Subway again: food poisoning 2009, terrible sandwich in Africa, now this - 3 strikes, never again! Thankfully we keep all our valuables on our bodies, so all that was in my bag was clothing. While I'm sad to lose some things picked up on the road, I know the robber will be disappointed with all the dirty underwear and lack of electronics/passport/value. Cheers to lighter travel!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_cadf1f26036b49758fb0da32a44869cb~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b661c761a8ae4202b9e61d947599b6c7~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_17010a95b49f4b4abbccc07361d9a92e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_36e8e6167e0c419fa7048ef9a11d03c4~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a8f558213d7d4282ba40aa3342266f17~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c24495ff82fb483fb2ff5cc38d50a86a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0084376eb7654afb9513af84eb0ca6b8~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d9d6257427d244eb93c3e39c687f116c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e4b40fed74014950b8203d3f76b5999d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0199c55123284308a9b9b4836b3ca21b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dbe0c71a32904e538ac3136f7abf9509~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_86e75b39bee942eb90865f138606a70f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a5f1d33ed4fd4d1290392ac1b3504bf0~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e15a302cf7e24190b8b6e2f72ca7e518~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Brie'n up in Joburg - Johannesburg, South Africa</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
After our long bus adventure back to Joburg we were picked up by our new S. African friends (Quintin and Lorette) that we met in Uganda while rafting the Nile. They took us straight to their friends house in Pretoria because they were having themselves a Briie (Afrikaans for BBQ). After an hour drive we ended up in a swanky, gated community with palm trees. And their friends turned out to be an up-and-coming Afrikaans girl band, "Saarkie." We had ourselves a great time, eating local meat, having<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9020ab989ad04d22992ed34445377ec1%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/01/Brien-up-in-Joburg---Johannesburg-South-Africa-1
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/06/01/Brien-up-in-Joburg---Johannesburg-South-Africa-1
</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>After our long bus adventure back to Joburg we were picked up by our new S. African friends (Quintin and Lorette) that we met in Uganda while rafting the Nile. They took us straight to their friends house in Pretoria because they were having themselves a Briie (Afrikaans for BBQ). After an hour drive we ended up in a swanky, gated community with palm trees. And their friends turned out to be an up-and-coming Afrikaans girl band, &quot;Saarkie.&quot; We had ourselves a great time, eating local meat, having some drinks, and chillin' with hipster crew of SA. Later that evening they took us out to a ranch sorta place for an Afrikaburn-themed birthday party. Think really small/laid back Burning Man. They burned a wooden cat sculpture. I burned a bale of hay. The next day Quintin and Lorette dropped us off at the metro and we parted ways. Laura and I had some time to kill, so we went and checked out the Nelson Mandela Plaza. Basically a big shopping mall with a big statue of Nelson. We found a Cinnabon. Life is good.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_094c0d75a0634c4db81e94ffcde6dea0~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9020ab989ad04d22992ed34445377ec1~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_73dc20847bf749ce8f6ed38209cf11d4~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cape Town - Cape Town, South Africa</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We had talked to a few locals in Cape Town through the website couchsurfing.org (CS) prior to arriving. The website connects travelers interested in a 'local experience' with locals willing to open up their homes, interested in learning about other cultures and making friends from around the world. You are able to read all reviews about the people - good and bad - and also talk to them before agreeing to stay together. There is also a certification process. And don't worry - someone always knew<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e826aecd322a4696833486ffed90abfa%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/30/Cape-Town---Cape-Town-South-Africa-1
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/30/Cape-Town---Cape-Town-South-Africa-1
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We had talked to a few locals in Cape Town through the website couchsurfing.org (CS) prior to arriving. The website connects travelers interested in a 'local experience' with locals willing to open up their homes, interested in learning about other cultures and making friends from around the world. You are able to read all reviews about the people - good and bad - and also talk to them before agreeing to stay together. There is also a certification process. And don't worry - someone always knew where we were for safety. We got off the 20-hour bus ride from Johannesburg and got on another bus that took us 30 minutes from Cape Town to beautiful Hout Bay and the home of Maarten (2 minutes from the beach). He has hosted dozens upon dozens of people, loves to travel, and also does home exchanges and rents his three places out to vacation-goers. He is a wealth of knowledge on the area. The night we arrived we all walked down to the harbor to see the overweight seals, and then to dinner at a delicious restaurant near the beach. The next day Maarten dropped Mark and I off at the base of Table Mountain. We hiked up and down the giant geological table, stopping for a long lunch on top (there is also a cable car, but we thought we could use the exercise). Maarten was at a work meeting, so Mark and I stocked up to make ultimate salads (yes, salads - turns out we miss them) at the grocery store, and caught up on some chores we had been avoiding. Maarten took Friday off to bring us to Cape Horn. On the way we stopped at South Africa's oldest winery, Bolder's Beach (home of a bunch of endangered, funny looking penguins), a gem factory, and a beach for a picnic. Cape Horn was windy as all get-out, but absolutely spectacular. It's famous for being the southernmost tip of Africa, but is really second or third in line. I have a feeling the country just decided to label it as furthest south for tourism. It was crazy to see where two oceans come together (Indian and Atlantic). We also visited another nearby point, the Cape of Good Hope. On the way back home we stopped by an ostrich farm for some coffee, and to have our hands pecked at by impressively strong beaks. After a 30 cent McDonalds ice cream and a beautiful sunset in a schnazzy neighborhood, we went to a crazy indoor market that is only on Fridays. It takes place in an old warehouse by the ocean. They decorate the whole thing, bring in vendors, delicious food, and livebands. It is absolutely beautiful, and hipster-tastic. The next day we were passed off to another CS host, Ofer (and his two mini greyhound dogs: Romeo and Fabio). He lives in Table View, on the opposite side of Cape Town. Our first night we all went out to dinner by the waterfront before watching the European soccer championship on TV. Ofer is part of a hiking group, so we joined the crew for their weekly Sunday hike. They are definitely in shape! We trekked through beautiful rainforest-like trails, passing waterfalls and swinging on vines. After a few hours we reached Kirstenbosh, the area's botanical gardens. We filled ourselves with cake and coffee before making our way back to a memorial monument near the cars. That night Ofer had a date, so Mark and I took the opportunity for our own. We went to the mall for the typical dinner and a movie. It was Mark's turn to choose, so we watched the new X-men. I fell asleep. Monday was the day all my South African dreams came true. I had arranged the event of a lifetime, and was willing to get up at 4:30 AM to do it. What was I so excited about, you may ask? ...GREAT WHITE SHARK CAGE DIVING!! After 3 hours of travel, a delicious breakfast, and a boat ride to &quot;shark alley&quot; (between &quot;seal island&quot; and Dyer island) the blood bath began! The sharks were tempted with giant chunks of bait, pieces of fish swirled into water and dumped overboard, and a styrofoam cutout of a seal named 'Henrietta' (who caught a shark tooth in her side during the first attack). We were given 7 mm wetsuits and goggles before entering the cage hanging from the side of the boat. With every pass of the sharks we would hold our breath and watch them come within inches of our face, attacking the well-placed bait. I went in the cage for three half-hour stints, despite the frigid water. It was too amazing not to. As we were heading back to mainland for food and to watch the movie, a shark jumped straight up out of the water. Absolutely incredible! And of course no boat ride is complete without Mark getting seasick. Five minutes before docking he filled a barf bag. After my time spent in shark alley, I am now confident that I will never go surfing in Cape Town. That night Ofer taught us to make shokshooka, an Israeli dish (Ofer is from Israel) made of spicy tomato soup and boiled eggs. Delicious. Tuesday Mark and I finally went into downtown Cape Town. We wandered Loop and Long, the shopping streets. We went to a tap house, saw the up-and-coming Woodstock neighborhood, and had a local beer at the Devils Peak Brewing Company. On Wednesday we met Ofer's business partner. They use a laser cutter to cut materials (records, cds, fabric, wood, etc) into things (clocks, coasters, jewelry, boxes, etc). It was amazing to watch the machine work and see the results. His partner (who was unfortunately making an urn for her father) even gave me a small wood cutout of Africa for a necklace. That afternoon we were passed on to our final hosts, Carole and Tony in Glencairn, one of the towns farthest south. Once their daughters moved to England they decided to start hosting travelers. The way to their house is over a stunning pass on a cliff over the ocean. Tony is a carpenter, and built their amazing and quirky home himself. The kitchen is built using part of the mountain as a wall, the upstairs bathrooms have glass roofs, and Tony built a lot of the furniture using teak wood from travels to Thailand. They treated us to a homemade South African dinner that was absolutely delicious. Moulva pudding... yes I got the recipe! The next day we walked up through the coastal towns along the beach, and took the train back to make our hosts our newly learned recipe: shokshooka. Friday was Mark's birthday! Carole made him a delicious cake and bag of goodies for our long bus ride back to Johannesburg. I took Mark out for sushi (his favorite) downtown. It pays to be near the water! Having broken our camera in a cave earlier in the week, we also bought a new one. We took the bus for a quick trip to the waterfront, an area of fun shops and restaurants. Then it was off on another 22-hour bus ride back to Johannesburg! The best way to end a birthday.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_aaa22ec3216846f592110eb7d96495f9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b2408a02036041e09589ce5c5420f495~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_bff4a209d0dc456a97a190eb333dfef6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_bb752fcc8e5f4ddb88cfc32190a79822~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_812f6ba827734743b5982446ab49f31a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1f37ec70a057448093c27cd536598e4f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_cf1668d5919e49848611da483c794ef5~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5d15c5361a124c36a7bd8233745db1d9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0d1abc82e9b54dbf8e31c1321c9f0e93~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2d990db7a9ef4b4993326b82dcf88a9b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_70ec87da9c184c98a3456d264bb4c55c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_560b0705488044b3a096918d3f900dde~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_94ca942d1f0d4ea59df0cba9f3f3470e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_83aa8a47c2ca4de1a730a851dff0687d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_68fcb297bffe468ca269d605ef03599a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e826aecd322a4696833486ffed90abfa~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_001d4cc2b4d44d4e9cbb53d35c19b8d4~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_665e380ad3f846bc95d83c238fd37877~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c1b2289747ac421e94032324a723e0f1~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_93ec17d0c82a41a3bc41c58924b714fa~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Taste of Johannesburg - Johannesburg, South Africa</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Flying to South Africa (cheaply) wasn't the most logical thing in the world. Uganda -> Rwanda -> Ethiopia -> S. Africa. We flew Ethiopian Air and decided that Ethiopians have a really cool language. Spoken, and (especially) written. We spent 2 nights in Joburg. The nights were spent inside our hostel because night time is a "no-go" in the city. Unless you're gangsta enough... which Laura and I are still trying to improve on. One of the days we just chilled, but the next day we spent at the<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3ea7d0d9261341aa8142a7db5fd06e6d%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/20/Taste-of-Johannesburg---Johannesburg-South-Africa-1
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/20/Taste-of-Johannesburg---Johannesburg-South-Africa-1
</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Flying to South Africa (cheaply) wasn't the most logical thing in the world. Uganda -&gt; Rwanda -&gt; Ethiopia -&gt; S. Africa. We flew Ethiopian Air and decided that Ethiopians have a really cool language. Spoken, and (especially) written. We spent 2 nights in Joburg. The nights were spent inside our hostel because night time is a &quot;no-go&quot; in the city. Unless you're gangsta enough... which Laura and I are still trying to improve on. One of the days we just chilled, but the next day we spent at the Apartheid museum. It was huge and took us more than 4 hours to walk through. The museum had a special exhibit on Nelson Mandela as a tribute to his life and recent passing. While walking through we ran into Lorien, a friend of Laura's growing up. Small world. Next stop: Cape Town. 22 hours by bus. We're pro at traveling by now. Ain't no thang.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_267fcd0ad49b413787bb5acbc0ec2f9b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3ea7d0d9261341aa8142a7db5fd06e6d~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Come, Let's Dance - Nansana, Ugand</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Our next stop was with an organization called 'Come, Let's Dance' in Nansana, Uganda. It was started by three locals and one westerner. CLD has a children's home, school, farm, clinic, and craft project/community center. Mark's friend Morgan has been involved with CLD for 7 years and is currently living at their volunteer house with his new bride. We were greeted by the volunteers, Morgan, Beth (his wife), and her delicious no-bake chocolate oatmeal cookies. Delicious. Our time was spent at<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_beb41e8cdcc04a08953d5f6437f7ef59%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/17/Come-Lets-Dance---Nansana-Ugand
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/17/Come-Lets-Dance---Nansana-Ugand
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 18:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Our next stop was with an organization called 'Come, Let's Dance' in Nansana, Uganda. It was started by three locals and one westerner. CLD has a children's home, school, farm, clinic, and craft project/community center. Mark's friend Morgan has been involved with CLD for 7 years and is currently living at their volunteer house with his new bride. We were greeted by the volunteers, Morgan, Beth (his wife), and her delicious no-bake chocolate oatmeal cookies. Delicious. Our time was spent at Thread of Life, the farm, or the school/clinic. All are a taxi ride away from 'base camp'. 'Thread of Life', CLD's sewing and craft project, is built as a community center near a major slum in Kampala. The community is welcome to use the beautiful plot of land for church meetings, picnics, whatever. TOL hosts weekly English class, sewing courses, and savings circles. There are also apartments on the property that they are renting out for income until TOL makes enough money to sustain all of its programs independently. The savings circles are set up so that each person commits to coming and bringing at least a small amount of money weekly. They record their savings in a book before giving the money and ledger to the three facilitators. The money and records are checked in front of the group. The group decides on the savings period (typically 6 months - 1 year. Those in the circle are allowed to take a loan out against the group pot that is less than or equal to double their contributions to-date. The group agrees on an interest rate that will be spread based on shares in the pot once the loan is repaid. Each member is given their total savings (plus interest) at the end of the savings period. This model has proven successful for CLD and is used at many of its projects. Women are found in the nearby slums for the sewing course. A patient teacher and lots of practice are key to the class' success. While with CLD, we were able to see a graduation ceremony for approximately 10 women. They all showed off the clothes they learned to make, made speeches thanking God and their class, and shared hopes for the future. All planned to continue practicing at TOL, and hope to get successful jobs as tailors. Of course I couldn't resist the excellent skills of the women and also the great prices. So after a shopping afternoon in Kampala and a few days of waiting, I took home a beautiful skirt...and a few things from their craft shop...while Mark fixed their solar power. The 'Double Portion Farm&quot; is centered around a revolutionary way of farming called 'Farming God's Way'. This method is easy and beneficial for local farmers, as it is expected to produce 14x regular yield within seven seasons (Uganda is the only place where they can get 2 seasons per year). It also calls for work to be done by hand (not with expensive machinery), for utilizing pulled weeds and compost as a blanket for crops, and for the land to never be burned. The four principles of the program are: high standards, on time, with joy, and without wastage. Mark and I spent our time weeding (and laying the weeds back on the ground), and top dressing (digging small holes next to each corn stock to give vitamins to each plant). We were sore for days. Our evening at the farm consisted of playing with 2-day old goats, a puppy, and a fresh baby cow (which unfortunately died later in the week after ingesting a plastic bag). After a campfire, we went to bed under a giant shelter, using our bug net as a tent. All the Ugandans were shocked and thought we would freeze to death (it was an 80+ degree day). Sleeping was great until the storm hit. The wind blew the rain right into us, so we quickly shuffled around to a couple more locations before finding a dry place that would work. A farm really is a beautiful place to wake up (as long as you're not soaking wet). School was on break for the entire month we were in Uganda. This made visiting the school a bit boring, but still fun to see. The clinic proved to be exciting when a swarm of thousands of ants were discovered in the lab. Thankfully the neighborhood kids were good at stomping. Mark and I bought some de-worming pills (most volunteers in Uganda take them as a precaution every 3 months), as 9 months in the developing world is very likely to have given us something. Mark also took time to fix the clinic's electrical wiring, which was shoddily done back in the day. Mark met a guy named Peter when he first came to Uganda with CLD in 2008. They became friends working at the farm, and kept in touch on Facebook. Mark helped him out with a semester's tuition to go back to school after dropping out. Now, Peter just graduated as salutatorian of his high school! He is expected to get a full-ride scholarship to study civil engineering at a nearby university. All this to say, Peter came by with a friend to say hi to Mark, meet me, and eat some delicious dinner. Africa lived up to it's reputation of pests, as we received lots of mosquito bites (yes, we are on malaria pills), bed bugs from an infested chair in the house, and came away from the farm with new friends: jiggers (small white worms that burry themselves under your skin). Mark had one in his hand, and I had three on my feet. Thankfully Nurse Ana and her fancy needle work was able to teach us how to poke them - and their eggs - out. Side note: shampoo was VERY hard to find near Nansana. Hair oil: easy. Shampoo: hard. Conditioner: impossible. Reading my book &quot;When Helping Hurts&quot;, remembering my college 3rd World Development class, talking to people, and visiting non-profits has us thinking more about the right way to go about aid in the developing world. This means lots of research into where our money is going. We don't have the answers yet, but are enjoying the process.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_682c04fbb29e4d5c9df0b503d6d54e83~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_beb41e8cdcc04a08953d5f6437f7ef59~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_206f3008ae4645dfb338dd7f991969b5~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_66024f258d504aaaae3c7514993f4a1b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_91436e9941a64940bd8d0aaab23ce510~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5d572265ae1a4881b015931d0ca3c2fb~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b35b8de9a72244a8b6815e9d35a6e046~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_827282b8b8ef41c8b940ef762bb90121~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4c663c6180d547938634d7e611680700~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_62481345630541cca3785568d7220b87~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3703bdeaa0d245e7b43a024b14a5ebea~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_95928430c07442058121280fd74795d6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_86a6e73e3ba14928b1ce5ab7afc08cb6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_93b5599f2f514afabf2040ae624faa15~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f520ae1647e343be9f47a1dcd23b2bef~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Safari! - Masindi, Uganda</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
(Self note: We actually split up our time at Come Let's Dance (see next blog) by taking a safari on one of the weekends) Mark and I had compared packages, asked for advice, and looked forward to our Ugandan safari for weeks. Merchison National Park, we were told, is the place to go. We teamed up with Brin (who we met at Musana), and her visiting mom, to make the ultimate 4-person safari dream team. After a 4-hour bus ride from Kampala to Masindi, we checked into our adorable cottage at the New<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2e3b1cde7f7c43ae98879edb1ea947fe%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/12/Safari---Masindi-Uganda
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/12/Safari---Masindi-Uganda
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>(Self note: We actually split up our time at Come Let's Dance (see next blog) by taking a safari on one of the weekends) Mark and I had compared packages, asked for advice, and looked forward to our Ugandan safari for weeks. Merchison National Park, we were told, is the place to go. We teamed up with Brin (who we met at Musana), and her visiting mom, to make the ultimate 4-person safari dream team. After a 4-hour bus ride from Kampala to Masindi, we checked into our adorable cottage at the New Court View Hotel (recommended by Ryan and Sarah, our friends in Burundi). A pleasant break from community living. We met our private driver, Moses, who insisted that he could call any guide in the park to talk about sightings and take us to all the animals in the park the next day. I didn't sleep well and woke up with a 'hokey tummy'. Translated: I skipped the complimentary breakfast. We made the 1.5 hour dirt road drive into the park, and to the ferry - just in time to miss the 9AM crossing. Finding ourselves with an hour and a half to kill, we picked up some sandwiches and enjoyed the peaceful view of the Nile. Once on the other side, the safari began! Taking off down the dirt road, Moses led us through the game park. Elephants, giraffes, water buffalo, birds, cobys, and a bunch of animals new to me passed within feet of our red pickup. It was absolutely incredible to see animals in their natural habitats. Giraffes are much taller than what I remember from the zoo. The only things we didn't feast our eyes on were the big cats. Turns out Moses wasn't completely honest with us the night before, as another group at our hotel was able to see both cats. I guess that's the luck of the draw! My cramping stomach evolved throughout the day into frequent trips to the bathroom, cramps, and a fever. I'll spare you further details. The feeling was eerily familiar to the delightful sickness I had in Thailand, India and Nepal. Knowing it was better to avoid food rather than wake up hugging the toilet, I fasted the rest of the day. Determined to enjoy the rest of my first safari, we moved on to visit a swanky river-view hotel and then to the famous Merchison Falls. We were shocked at the amount of water powering through a narrow canyon. It was absolutely incredible. When we got back, I spent the night watching Aliens 2 on our Ipad (a much better movie than I expected). Feeling spoiled by a bit of luxury, we made our way back to Kampala by bus. We continued the vacation by visiting The Little Donkey restaurant to get our Mexican food fix. Satisfied and feeling better from the Mexican food 'medicine', we took a taxi van back to our friends at Come Let's Dance (see next blog).</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4e7976bfe16042a9a463e685a7153160~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ebd5a9b4aeef46edaf9be9528008302c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1d17664ade3741d9b1e9193f2c55021b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_84cc0e84a58c496ba6034e681ddc7e8a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9b7771971c934b35958e41f7c4e0c94e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e1895aa3bf274ba0b6c3d7b89b7bae34~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8870af46e2f348d2a0f47395928e4ce3~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_fd7e21fe1c1346db88844e1a9f2bc03d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4d0ba95e31314b1a90810d82ae6c7c09~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b21101781ef24116b438591a34b9b727~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2e3b1cde7f7c43ae98879edb1ea947fe~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3c5e276706954e0d82d34df1178469a9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6a16349f4a2f4b80874567f297cff617~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0a76ddd800bd4217a4375a745db60b55~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_339c6e8ca5f94ec1821dff268a27368f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e7d18e55b38947ee995fc4bef85305a1~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ccefc878e240464f8f85a6f437cc9848~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_75c18d84445845ab856ce2cabc4fec7f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ea47e2b47369461f9455c4b2fe191ced~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9113fc8345334477b2cc6727ecd81df5~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rafting the Nile River - Jinja, Uganda</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Mark has talked about rafting the Nile River for years. He would always say things like "rafting the Nile is way more intense than this" (during any water activity), or reminisce with friends about the exhilarating experience. Even though he had already rafted it twice in 2008, Mark felt it imperative to take me down the Nile during our time in Uganda. I quickly and enthusiastically agreed. We left Musana early Friday morning with Pat (a retired Canadian with a zest for adventure), and Yvonne<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6d4ab0bd5d4b4b11b96c07bcd0917c1b%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/04/Rafting-the-Nile-River---Jinja-Uganda
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/04/Rafting-the-Nile-River---Jinja-Uganda
</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Mark has talked about rafting the Nile River for years. He would always say things like &quot;rafting the Nile is way more intense than this&quot; (during any water activity), or reminisce with friends about the exhilarating experience. Even though he had already rafted it twice in 2008, Mark felt it imperative to take me down the Nile during our time in Uganda. I quickly and enthusiastically agreed. We left Musana early Friday morning with Pat (a retired Canadian with a zest for adventure), and Yvonne (another Canadian who was terrified to join us, but ready to cross it off her bucket list). After a matatu ride (white taxi vans that go everywhere in Uganda, holding 14+ people) we transferred to a giant raft-mobile. The raft-mobile's structure was obviously built in Uganda, with enough engine power to tow a few dozen people and rafts for all. We tore down local streets for an hour, making our way past a newly-built dam to the start of our epic adventure. We were joined in our raft by Robert, a 20-something oil digging Polish man, and Hassan, a 20-something local guide. After convincing Yvonne and Robert that &quot;extreme&quot; was the correct choice for the day, we tore off down the class 4 and 5 rapids. The rapids included a 15+ foot waterfall, falls in the river resulting in significant time underwater (we were instructed to ball up and &quot;find your happy place&quot;) until re-surfacing, and paddling into giant waves. Paddling through the waves made me feel like a pirate on the open sea. But for the sake of the raft, it is a good thing none of us had peg legs or hook hands. Halfway through the day we reached a rapid called &quot;the bad place&quot;. We somehow made it through, but there was one casualty: Yvonne's big toenail. Ouch. We were given breakfast, lunch on the river (pineapples and crackers), and an absolutely epic barbecue at the end of the day. Vegetable curry, rolls, hummus, potatoes, some of the best beef of my life (next to my parent's blue cheese steak), and an open bar. Happy, exhausted, and full, we went back to the riverside Nile River Explorers hostel. We spent the evening talking to a couple from South Africa (the next county on our list), and now have a &quot;br-eye&quot; (BBQ) to look forward to in Johannesburg. We spent the next day relaxing in Jinja. Wandering town, looking at art, catching up on the internet, and eating some amazing food (including a legit Indian dinner).</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6d4ab0bd5d4b4b11b96c07bcd0917c1b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_493d4ecbcf2c4ca595e741358655817a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_115f1a6f354c4f4dbde42f72c86eb570~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_73c6707fd44144829b1d42f4b7426e3a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dea5570e40e848d2a3adce0411f6a15d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_63d5603d814f4df3935f915e94ea6484~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_921c4e1c047241b5b69843b610211f75~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_84a8be4e49764b2a80e8b87e220712d6~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Musana - Iganga, Kigali, Uganda</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Our travel time from Kigali to Iganga was a good 16 hours using all transfer means available: Taxi to bus to minivan (with a record 22 people inside) to boda (motorbike taxi). But everything went as smooth as it can, as far as ground transportation in Africa is concerned. The reason we trekked our way up to Iganga was to visit our friend AP. She started a community development organization there called Musana when I first visited Uganda in 2008. It's freaking awesome. They have all sorts of<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dd223208769448de9ebad9f9edd905df%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/02/Musana---Iganga-Kigali-Uganda
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/05/02/Musana---Iganga-Kigali-Uganda
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Our travel time from Kigali to Iganga was a good 16 hours using all transfer means available: Taxi to bus to minivan (with a record 22 people inside) to boda (motorbike taxi). But everything went as smooth as it can, as far as ground transportation in Africa is concerned. The reason we trekked our way up to Iganga was to visit our friend AP. She started a community development organization there called Musana when I first visited Uganda in 2008. It's freaking awesome. They have all sorts of things going on. A primary school, dormitories, dairy farm, restaurant, etc. They also conduct micro-loans for women, are building a secondary school, and a mushroom farm. Their O&amp;M budget is 70% sustainable and growing. Ok - enough of the sales pitch, but here's a link to their website if you're interested: musana.org AP is now married to an awesome Ugandan dude named Haril. They are living in Iganga most of the time managing Musana. Our goal was to provide help with any sort of grunt work needed. Which really meant playing with the kids, digging ditches, and tagging along on village meetings. Playing with the kids was probably more exhausting than digging ditches. Even though I grew up playing soccer, I got completely destroyed by children 15 years younger than me. They literally dribbled around me and through me. If we weren't playing soccer, they were braiding our hair or asking us to supervise them in the computer lab. Most of our ditch digging was to divert water drainage away from Musana's fish farm, as the dirty (trash) water was killing the fish. We also helped make fish food. Yep, fish food. How many people have the privilege of saying they've done that! Last were village meetings, which were centered around micro-loans and business development. Especially for the women. Laura actually had a dress made by one of the ladies who was hired on by Musana. On Sunday we went to a local church service that most of the Musana staff goes to. The music was LOOOOOOUUDD. It's almost like a competition to see which church can worship louder than the other. We also had a nice conversation with the local teachers. In Ugandan culture, you're not a man unless you have a baby. Therefore they encouraged me to &quot;plant the seed&quot; before we go home and surprise everybody. After a few laughs, one of the men insisted that we trade wives for fun. His wife seemed to be legitimately on board with the idea (polygamy here is fairly normal as well). But Ugandan woman are used to receiving a dowry (which I told her I did not pay for Laura), therefore she immediately lost all interest in the idea. Not to mention we're monogomists. On that happy note - I will end this blog entry. Off to Jinja for Nile River Rafting!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dd223208769448de9ebad9f9edd905df~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_24152c10db174655b225b4cd51c5d11b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_bb137bf019f24f9a90007fc1eebb3c65~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_68ba4f16c9884436b869cab0ffcd62d2~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7705f37a17874a85a013e241c96ca41a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5da90687d5ff42b8852c9197f4941c85~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d7aa80c9c0104281a030509c519b7f06~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f0e65f0b87fd4a9ab43602a801e1df1f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_357c78e0c2d64453a5a43fad2aa10b67~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0d49e9fa2af54787a8e878df0bc161b1~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_151a7638fda3429094f84f28a3b019fa~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f5c7303399364207abf97dd8d26151d9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_63b08d08a9a440c08ebfafa8eb8901bb~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a130484e04e34d10bc6fb404c8d85abf~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0742753c954140ef9b09509b67f26d5e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_723e39a39fba4a348334ca37fb848c37~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e033fbad307f478c9aa076a6300e41e1~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0fa3e7beb3604b989c25fcfd6202d143~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b0d1b5c9f184452e936950f2d8454e42~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b563e5d938864d4ea6f2eb0b418f965b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_34616d9e31924d6c9ab0776a1e3dcc9e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e0e37c696af445988984dbaef576fd90~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0eeaece75263437b9541c8a6eca20317~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_88b6b32b92a14d638affc74980b73d2c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_cc5bba3dfdf64951a33ced38cc1b7b7f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_55692d2f912a4ee8ba46715fdfe4705f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_db46494d91dc4d86815c4e0f4d962cc9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3fdfe630903347649bd3afae4f73385a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_658951b006a848308f8ecac32cbafa8f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_276411c7c9fd484fab56199df85d1faa~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3433b5062255409eb7c78b2d20640cf6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5f60fa5f4ed74e70946898d36c6c3738~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_48d015d801e34c70acce0d719ef39f6c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_16598be861e9469bb29d180d2112bbaf~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6c6164cd1e8743f5ba8fa02e8585b0e2~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_da5715c7065d4e80a5bfe4246650b982~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a9e4fe4d0c2f4df09a1723744a8b2789~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ed62ff61f4804ebabfc30d73db7329e8~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a4db0bceb9e94f34b40631035636468f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8085e92c8e3c4a0ebaa6836975908be0~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rwanda - Kigali, Rwanda</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
At the airport on the way to Kigali, Rwanda, Mark and I were again given trouble about being siblings. The man checking us in told us that we couldn't be married, as we have the same last name. After denying incest and explaining that my last name used to be 'Bischoff', he finally believed us. When checking my bag, he referred to it as "mama's" bag. He insisted that we would have babies soon. Mark was also asked by a few people if he would be speaking at the genocide 20 year anniversary<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0593b414d474407687143267781845a3%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/21/Rwanda---Kigali-Rwanda
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/21/Rwanda---Kigali-Rwanda
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>At the airport on the way to Kigali, Rwanda, Mark and I were again given trouble about being siblings. The man checking us in told us that we couldn't be married, as we have the same last name. After denying incest and explaining that my last name used to be 'Bischoff', he finally believed us. When checking my bag, he referred to it as &quot;mama's&quot; bag. He insisted that we would have babies soon. Mark was also asked by a few people if he would be speaking at the genocide 20 year anniversary remembrance activities going on in Rwanda. Apparently his long hair (somehow) gives him an air of professionalism. Elias was a little trooper during the 30-minute flight. Rwanda is clean, organized, and even has traffic lights with a count-down system (although it does get stuck at &quot;0&quot; a lot). It is considered one of the least corrupt and most forward-moving countries in Africa. Our guest house was beautiful. It had an amazing view overlooking the city, and included a delicious buffet breakfast each morning. Friday was Elias' day for shots. We all went to a small clinic in the Belgian Embassy, where he entered with his parents to brave the needles. Mark and I wandered the block until we found some giant terradactyl-looking birds in a giant grass field on the other side of a fence. Mark took a few photos before I noticed a man with a bug gun and an angry face coming toward us. He asked why we were taking pictures of the government house, declaring sternly that &quot;we have a problem&quot;. Thankfully he soon realized that we were just clueless tourists, and let us go on our merry way. Next stop was a mall for diapers and coffee. There was a movie theater on the top floor. Mark and I went to check out the day's movies, but found that none were listed on the screens. After a wait we were handed a printed piece of paper from deep inside a drawer, boasting five movies and times. How To Train Your Dragon 2 wasn't on the list (we were hoping it was because the first movie is awesome), and we hadn't heard of any of the other movies, so we decided to pass. Lunch was BURRITOS! A man who had worked for a California Chipotle started up a restaurant in town. It was the same idea, but also included options for goat meat and pineapple/mango salsa. Guacamole was free, but sour cream cost extra - opposite of home. Lucky Africa...able to grow everything! That afternoon we visited the Rwanda Trading Company. They're a local company that processes and packages coffee for places like Folger's and Starbucks (among other places). They were closed, but a nice guy from Arkansas was in his office to show us around. On Saturday we went to the Rwanda Genocide Museum. Here is a link to a site with a short history of the genocide if you want to read up: http://history1900s.about.com/od/rwandangenocide/a/Rwanda-Genocide.htm The museum was packed because we were there during the 20th anniversary month. Entrance is free, as they want everyone to come. Inside the building you are led to walk along a timeline of the events leading up to the genocide. Next is a history of the killings, and also an area to honor the victims with personal pictures hanging on the walls. We also passed through a room highlighting personal details of the children who were killed. The top floor included an exhibit on genocide in general, including definitions and other examples throughout history. The Rwandans keep the genocide discussion in the open. Memorials are also intentionally set up as places to teach children. They want to keep discussions going to prevent something similar from ever happening again. Hutus and Tutsis (the two groups that clashed in the genocide) are no longer distinguished in society. We were really impressed. On the flip side, there are rumors of the government in Burundi training child soldiers in preparation for the upcoming 2015 elections. People in Burundi are generally less educated, and still identify as Hutu or Tutsi. Chatter and speculations are swirling, everyone is hoping that a similar genocide is not on the horizon for Burundi. In the afternoon we went for a drink at the hotel from the movie &quot;Hotel Rwanda&quot;, where Mille Colline, a wealthy and well-known owner of the hotel hid hundreds of Tutsis during the genocide. You can get a cocktail named after him there. Highly recommend it. Sunday was Easter. We all went to a local church with lots of singing. It was just over 2 hours long, which is considered exceptionally short for an African church. After we were stopped in the parking lot by a local news station (who had been filming the church service) to say a few words about Easter and Rwanda. We were famous on the local news that night! We went for one last burrito (couldn't resist!) before saying goodbye to Ryan, Sarah, and Elias. They were absolutely amazing hosts and tour guides. Luckily they are also moving back to Boulder in 3 weeks, so we're looking forward to seeing them again soon! Mark and I stayed one more night before catching the 6AM bus the following morning to Iganga, Uganda.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0593b414d474407687143267781845a3~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7c9f4076da8440dbb9bd99e55a798d89~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2456154f59994ab293bc4783a2177923~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c7a092123bf247178409cbe95629e301~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7ca20df695b54ee78e0c65454c993fc4~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d41b7ea499114e8db896a5ad92c6ccf7~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a9e1080e6049409b9e52315d1a9cd481~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b17afd135ad24c27bf7c0a532739ed73~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_244c9d16c5ea4933b0ed689713930f82~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9f5d3ffcfd2c40c48831eca61a60ed6c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7b7619b1486945e5a798aa98090c3d33~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_377fad107d03485c834f322371606f08~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_23c6fb8c9578433e98c1e8a959672716~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c6c8e239256b48e2b2658b86f0f1ce67~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_023dd77ba6974518abdb31a5e9a6af90~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_fb1e8de756774441a6c7664133cbcf47~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_962e71f152954d6f9c63f6d7ba74f161~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4a66366b42fb42819b02045577ed5fac~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Guinea Pigs at the Museum - Bujumbura, Kigali, Burundi
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Our last day in Bujumbura was spent at Musee Vivant, the "museum" in town. Except it proved to be more of a makeshift zoo than a museum. On our drive there, along the lake, we were greeted by a bloat (yes, a bloat) of hippos. They were ENORMOUS! And every time their heads poked up through the water, their ears would spin and shake to get the water off. It was very entertaining. We arrived at Musee Vivant, not knowing that the next hour would be among the more entertaining - and emotional - so<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f1aa8a620711402e90087e32aa8ccf8c%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/17/Guinea-Pigs-at-the-Museum---Bujumbura-Kigali-Burundi
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/17/Guinea-Pigs-at-the-Museum---Bujumbura-Kigali-Burundi
</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Our last day in Bujumbura was spent at Musee Vivant, the &quot;museum&quot; in town. Except it proved to be more of a makeshift zoo than a museum. On our drive there, along the lake, we were greeted by a bloat (yes, a bloat) of hippos. They were ENORMOUS! And every time their heads poked up through the water, their ears would spin and shake to get the water off. It was very entertaining. We arrived at Musee Vivant, not knowing that the next hour would be among the more entertaining - and emotional - so far in Burundi. We were joined by a guide who gave us a tour of the grounds. We were shown crocodiles and alligators in cages with walls that seemed just a tiny bit too low. He assured us they were fine, and that they add bricks or taller fences as the animals grew bigger. He also told us about Gustov, the ginormous crocodile terror who is responsible for killing about 300 people in the nearby lake. He has been missing for a few years, presumedly to wreak havoc on the Congo side of the lake. We saw one aquarium of local fish, some monkeys, and a leopard eating a baby cow before being led to the snake house. Our guide detailed information about each snake, holding a few and offering them to us. A couple cages, including one holding live (thankfully non-venomous) snakes, had broken glass. One damaged cage was the result to over-eager children, and the other was from the zoo's chimpanzee who got upset, was somehow let loose, and went on a rampage. The last stop was the chimpanzee, swinging on a tire swing in her cage. As soon as she saw us (namely Elias) approaching, she jumped off and greeted us, hand out of the cage. She reached for Elias and gently held his foot. No reaction from him. As the responsible parents backed up (images of the woman mauled on Oprah in their heads), the chimpanzee made an overly-dramatic sad face. She tried to lure Ryan with a stick to bring Elias back. Her efforts unsuccessful, she chucked the stick at Ryan and swung madly around her cage. Before we left, we were offered a cage full of guinea pigs and rabbits to feed to the leopard or one of the many crocodiles. The men (Mark and Ryan) looked at each other and gave in, to the horror of Sarah and I. Thankfully Elias was asleep by now and missed the following chaos. A guinea pig was selected (with some squealing), and used by our guide to tease every animal we passed. Finally we arrived at the big croc's cage, where the guinea pig was used to tease him until we insisted that he put the little guy out of his misery. Our guide tossed the animal into the water, and it was quickly chomped by the crocodile mid-swim. All four of us left traumatized. That was one strange museum.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f1aa8a620711402e90087e32aa8ccf8c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c27d57450a4748609728cfb169ecfd5d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_fcaa3ed4b1eb44d5903db53f054bb302~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b83ef9b168484490b6427e02bc72f9ff~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8644009da69f41c6a57ba5732bc50496~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4cc1388b8dc04baeb038079aebbf2e52~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0cd2ee13b78f470bb8fbb7875cf90a88~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b33e4d1c89434e48bd149be6a77aae4e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_81f0f893c32341e7bfe833246ff38d1a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_32bdee430f824999ac09431e82320aa2~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_cc3025c9742c4fdbac76705f57683bac~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b319df64233342bb8d16f39c6e0ed2d2~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_91bc0fc9ee654cafba7e201d72a78409~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f96886f42a434460a607f5471dd65d8f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8b700f2a261d49a4b6eb166587fd7471~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ec40331608fd4c829e55189d9e417804~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5058d70ba10b4f43a504cbc56c71f138~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_08f8273d109a4124b8e98bf6a6f3b21b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3c1f6bc48776412885d1ad186b912853~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b4a95ac7591e4bf2b51b959ed97339d6~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kayanza: Field Visits - Kayanza, Kigali, Burundi</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Ryan works for Hope International, a micro-finance NGO that works to bring savings plans to the poor areas of the world. Burundi is the third poorest country in the world (according to some guy on the internet), under Zimbabwe and the Democratic Republic of the Congo (which can be seen across the lake from Bujumbura). Over half the population lives on less than $1.25 a day. Hope works with local churches to bring up leaders in the community to create savings groups. Burundi culture is very<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a01382baebe441f8b4da7c520678c489%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/15/Kayanza-Field-Visits---Kayanza-Kigali-Burundi
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/15/Kayanza-Field-Visits---Kayanza-Kigali-Burundi
</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Ryan works for Hope International, a micro-finance NGO that works to bring savings plans to the poor areas of the world. Burundi is the third poorest country in the world (according to some guy on the internet), under Zimbabwe and the Democratic Republic of the Congo (which can be seen across the lake from Bujumbura). Over half the population lives on less than $1.25 a day. Hope works with local churches to bring up leaders in the community to create savings groups. Burundi culture is very hospitable. If someone asks you for a loan and you have the money, you are culturally required to give it. The savings groups keep this in mind. Once a week the groups meet, each person bringing a set small amount of money. The money is pooled, and given to one member who immediately goes and buys something to make profit off of (a bag of food to re-sell, a down-payment on a store, a goat, etc). The member who gets the pot rotates weekly, so the group benefits each member. There is also another savings plan used in which group can pool money and choose to loan money to any one member if they feel the person can pay it back. Interest rates and payback period are determined by the group. Ryan, Sarah, Elias, and a friendly local Hope employee named Belize, took us out to Kayanza, a 2-hour drive into the hills. The plan was to visit some savings groups and see what they have been able to do. As soon as we left town, the poverty of Burundi became more apparent. On our way up, bike riders carrying water up to their homes hitched rides by holding onto the backs trucks. There could be 7+ riders nonchalantly holding onto one truck. On the way we bought two GIANT avocados (the size of large mangoes). They were delicious. We were greeted by the leader in Kayanza, who showed us around to different areas of town. Each project was shown to us by the project leader, and two other prominent people in the group. We were shown a bee hive project, a pig project, a chicken project, and a store financed through a loan from his group. The road was too washed out (and the new home of a giant fallen tree) to see the goat project, but the dozens of goats around town satisfied our goat quota for the month. It really was amazing to see what the simple savings plans allowed people to accomplish. You could see pride in their eyes as they talked about their projects' success. It was really encouraging to see such hope. The people in this region are extremely conservative Christians, so we were asked to remove all jewelry before going. Being foreigners, it was ok to have our hair done. But local women either wear headscarves or sport chic buzz cuts. We were completely swarmed by kids, wanting to touch our skin or practice the little english they learned in school. They especially found baby Elias entertaining. He was passed along from woman to woman, a big smile on his face. At one of our stops, while entertaining the kids so Sarah could breastfeed, we were approached through the crowd of giggling children by a drunk woman, yelling in Kurundi (the local language), throwing her head back, and blazing all her teeth in a crazed cackle. No one in town seemed surprised, and just shuffled her on her way. It was like something out of a movie. After a long and tiring day, we went to Cafe Gourmond (the French bakery in Bujumbura) for a delicious meal of paninis, cole slaw, juice, and pastries. Full and feeling better, we walked out to the car. There were about a dozen police officers with rifles surrounding it. Apparently the place we were directed to park in was not a parking space. It is required to parallel park on this particular street, even though other cars were parked as we were, and there was a car parked a stones-throw away under a sign on the sidewalk. Ryan's usual strategy of pretending not to know a word of French (everyone on Bujumbura speaks French and the local language, Kirundi) failed when the officer proved to be fluent in English. A $30 ticket later, we were back at home in bed. Ryan was glad it was only $30.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a01382baebe441f8b4da7c520678c489~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9f9189f5b1054b5089822a1152bd5ee9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f34fc9ed8bfd485aaca5b9f033923c3a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_749652f3bf2c4989a6f483f71d53127f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_37e8cd1c65b8473e9ddbde2be3cf05ca~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ec5e8038316b4a34910a39f7bf0b6309~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_360f65bf30304a38a26aca6dd184ced6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5e48cafdb0584a93875d7b873c90f986~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8c38dc23d4cc426db77893617cbed8ed~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_35405d775b9944f5bccc31b1e8eaa116~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_be7eefd7b08b4ba6871144699c044c9a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2ed7680fce054375b35122403f4b0b9f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b5ac6ed438d44b84bbbcb143428fdae9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_feae229ea0a84ad9a49aad612491009c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f109bacee5fa4ade8ff93e003249af56~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a33e75b20f184735883dbf6133d18007~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e6463bac2d74434b8466f1a09d1c1b35~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4a798d07cdeb461bb439c7e9aa1161cc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b0112f256b1243a684caeb388ba57de9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f5f43a0b374141aa9fdb81e49ea4c9d8~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mzungus Reunited at Last - Bujumbura, Burundi</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Mark and I arrived in the Bujumbura, Burundi airport after stops in Ethiopia, Uganda (which our airline added last-minute to combine two flights into one), and Rwanda. Walking away from the plane, we felt like we were in a movie. In the distance were beautiful green hills, the air smelled amazing, and the weather was perfect. Unfortunately the fairytale ended quickly at the visa counter, where we were informed that we could only pay in US dollars. They didn't take Visa, Mastercard, or even their<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2c47c9ae2a40447984abd299c3453c64%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/15/Mzungus-Reunited-at-Last---Bujumbura-Burundi
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/15/Mzungus-Reunited-at-Last---Bujumbura-Burundi
</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Mark and I arrived in the Bujumbura, Burundi airport after stops in Ethiopia, Uganda (which our airline added last-minute to combine two flights into one), and Rwanda. Walking away from the plane, we felt like we were in a movie. In the distance were beautiful green hills, the air smelled amazing, and the weather was perfect. Unfortunately the fairytale ended quickly at the visa counter, where we were informed that we could only pay in US dollars. They didn't take Visa, Mastercard, or even their own local currency. This was a new one for us. Thankfully Ryan magically showed up to greet us at the desk, somehow going reverse through security without a ticket. They offered to keep our passports overnight so we could bring USD the next day, but Ryan wasn't sure our passports would still be there. We tried to exchange some local currency at the airport, but were offered a rate much, much worse than advertised on the board. When pushed, the woman said &quot;we are the black market&quot;. The nearby cop didn't care and said she was the one to decide the rate. In the end we paid for one visa using dollars I had with me, and the other in local currency (after some persuasion) with a slightly less-bad exchange rate at the visa counter directly. Ryan drove us to his house where we were greeted by his wife, Sarah, and their absolutely adorable 3-month-old, Elias. The three of them bravely volunteered to spend the next two weeks with us. They live in a really nice 4-bedroom house in a gated compound guarded round-the-clock by three guards: one during the day and two at night. They also have an amazingly friendly house help named Emilianne. She does not speak English, but is very animated and gifted at charades. She has 2 of her own and 3 orphans at home. The guards and Emilianne stopped Mark and I at different times to ask if we were siblings. Mark had to make good on his wedding vows and insist that we are, in fact, married. Emilianne said she would pray to Jesus that we have babies. Mark and I pray to Jesus that we don't (yet) have babies. When we arrived, Mark and I were fed an amazing dinner by Sarah, who filled our stomaches our whole stay in Burundi with absolutely delicious home-cooked meals. Thankfully she taught me most of them, so I have some new recipes to try at home! Chickpea burgers, steaks, pasta casserole, quinoa burrito bowls... Food was much more expensive than we expected, especially in the main city of Bujumbura (where street food is not a thing). A lot of groceries, especially for cooking &quot;western&quot; meals, are imported and spread throughout different stores in town. Fruits and veggies are all washed (by Sarah) in a diluted bleach mixture to ward off any parasites. We even got to start every day with french press Burundi coffee and a chocolate croissant thanks to a nearby French bakery! As the ATMs in Burundi give terrible rates or are broken, Ryan took us on a field trip to his bank, where after some magic with our credit card, an hour and a half, and a $12 hidden fee, we were finally given $300 cash in US dollars. Only then were we able to get the &quot;ok&quot; black market rate at a nearby foreign exchange shop. With money in our hands Ryan and Sarah dropped us off downtown to get a feel for the city and people. Like every new country we visit, it took a few minutes to get used to being the only white people (&quot;mzungus&quot;) in sight. I even got about three people pointing and stating &quot;mzungu!&quot; to their friends, something I am told will be much more common in Uganda. Technically, mzungu means &quot;white wanderer.&quot; We went through a bunch of shops (which were small sheds) filled with masks and artifacts from the DRC, just across the lake from town. They were slightly creepy, especially the ones with fake hair, and were also home to numerous spiders. We picked up a SIM card, bananas, and passion fruit before making the short walk home in the afternoon heat. We spent the first few days relaxing at the Severns' house. Internet, a hot shower, shopping trips, and wonderfully delicious food. We even had time to sit down and watch the movies Crash (HIGHLY recommend), and Sweeny Todd (...unique, but I don't recommend). Having an energetic baby like Elias to play with and smile at all the time made the re-charge time even better. Since Americans (and Westerners in general) are a rare breed, we were invited to a US embassy party thrown by an athletic couple (he is in the military) and their kids. The shin-dig took place at their beautiful home on a hill outside town. Their yard was decked out with a slackline, volleyball net, swimming pool, and personal cook roasting a whole lamb under the gazeebo. Somehow about half of the people in attendance were from Colorado, so it was good to feel a bit like we were at home. Feeling inspired, Mark and I braved the embassy the next morning to get more pages in my passport. It was enormous! Armed guards, triple security, guards to chaperone you from place to place...they didn't even permit anyone to walk on the front sidewalk - you were required to pass to the other side of the street. A few days later we joined in an embassy softball game in a field next to where the president plays soccer. I'm not sure how there were 20 gloves and 3 bats available, but Mark and I had fun getting our exercise on. Even with my expert slow-pitching, Mark's team somehow won. No sport game in a foreign country is complete without Mark injuring himself - he came away with a messed up knee from ramming into the catcher at home plate. He didn't knock the catcher over (a ginormous marine). So yes... he was out. He's a little sore, but expected to make a full recovery :) Ryan's birthday fell in the middle of our stay. We celebrated by going out to a nice meal on one of the hills overlooking town. It felt a lot like the Flagstaff House, but the prices were much easier on the wallet. Beautiful AND delicious. We absolutely loved our time in Bujumbura. It was great to see friends and have time to relax, while still living in a completely new culture. Ryan and Sarah were EXTREMELY hospitable, making us feel right at home. As Mark so eloquently stated, &quot;this is the most at-home I have felt in months&quot;.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4cdf2475dfa14bfe9b574b44a1e64ecf~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_935967b349ad431e8370bc0f0b57663d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_44833cf2d524492c9e129fb2f9ca6e89~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4d3f0e4b4c3c4345b4b99f177c1ff9f3~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0ccfa856fffc4566b51c13adc8a6f388~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_99f5761b632a45f9be7dd9bcc1f74fd1~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d3a28c0ce4ab4e148bd5fee3f06c69d0~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a779f74f67f14cf589da274633851c52~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_afdac97ae7574c1081d136e650548c11~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2c47c9ae2a40447984abd299c3453c64~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Home Again - Tel Aviv, Israel</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Back on our cozy porch downtown Tel Aviv, we found ourselves yet again spoiled by Lev and Natalka. I stepped on a cross-eyed, autistic cat in the apartment stairwell (apparently a common occurrence, as he tries to run in front of residents). Thankfully for my conscience, I found him the next day, happy and with no fresh wounds, to apologize. After a failed attempt to pay for a delicious dinner of sushi and Thai food at the Tel Aviv Pier (Lev is stronger and speaks more Hebrew than us), we<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4f2fb859560e49e0a06073e3354de3f4%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/07/Home-Again---Tel-Aviv-Israel
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/07/Home-Again---Tel-Aviv-Israel
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Back on our cozy porch downtown Tel Aviv, we found ourselves yet again spoiled by Lev and Natalka. I stepped on a cross-eyed, autistic cat in the apartment stairwell (apparently a common occurrence, as he tries to run in front of residents). Thankfully for my conscience, I found him the next day, happy and with no fresh wounds, to apologize. After a failed attempt to pay for a delicious dinner of sushi and Thai food at the Tel Aviv Pier (Lev is stronger and speaks more Hebrew than us), we decided to make a Mexican feast for them on our last night. Natalka insisted on packing us snacks whenever we went out, so we were armed with fresh fruit and delicious home baked muffins for our last day in town. We ran errands, then bought flowers, magnum bars (necessary for any Mexican meal), every vegetable in the store, and even found tortillas! We definitely over-bought, but ended up with a meal that reminded Mark and I of home. One of our new friends from scuba diving, Danny, was able to come over and help eat, too. We were given the honor of sampling a taste of the vodka that Natalka's grandpa makes in Ukraine. Both her and Lev don't like it, so samples are reserved for guests. It wasn't as bad as they set it up to be. After feasting they brought us to the train station to begin our journey to the far-off land of Burundi, Africa!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4f2fb859560e49e0a06073e3354de3f4~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_59fa4c8e517a445dba76a1a185c3021e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_17165e78692f438088544cb16020c5b0~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6f918aeba4654b3ea3a304c3fc7ebfa5~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Red Sea Diving - Eilat, Israel</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Eilat was a world of it's own. The pale desert of both Eilat and Aqaba (the Jordanian city on the other side of the sea) made the deep blue of the Red Sea POP. Unfortunately despite it's name, the sea is not red (the name comes from the red of the nearby mountains). The city is built for tourism - both local and international, as seen by fancy hotels and expensive restaurants. When we went to the grocery store we were asked to show our passports. Odd. Then we were required to pay 5 shekels into<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_17896f3e90e74befa7133b5a3ac8a37d%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/05/Red-Sea-Diving---Eilat-Israel
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/05/Red-Sea-Diving---Eilat-Israel
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Eilat was a world of it's own. The pale desert of both Eilat and Aqaba (the Jordanian city on the other side of the sea) made the deep blue of the Red Sea POP. Unfortunately despite it's name, the sea is not red (the name comes from the red of the nearby mountains). The city is built for tourism - both local and international, as seen by fancy hotels and expensive restaurants. When we went to the grocery store we were asked to show our passports. Odd. Then we were required to pay 5 shekels into the grocery cart, a deposit to be returned upon putting the cart back in place after shopping. This is common throughout the whole country. Mark and I settled into our hostel, soon to be joined by eight Israelis (including Lev and Natalka). After a late dinner it was off to bed. We shared a room with a guy named Nimrod (be sure to say it with an Israeli accent) and his beautiful golden retriever, Mika. Thank goodness for allergy pills! Our first day was spent at the beach with our new roommates, Lev, and Natalka. The water was cold, and Mika could not be satisfied playing fetch no matter how many times her ball was thrown into the water. That night we all went out to a shnazzy dinner at a steakhouse. And the next day....SCUBA DIVING!! Our large group all went out to dive at a reef off shore (beautiful) and also at a sunken missile boat. Thankfully the missiles were removed. The boat dive was one of the best we have done so far on our trip. It was fun to explore inside, visibility was exceptional, and the swarms of fish were absolutely incredible. After diving we were given a VIP ride back to Tel Aviv with Nimrod. He took us the scenic route past Egypt's border, through the desert, and to an absolutely enormous crater viewpoint. He taught us about Israel's history of neighboring attacks, and we taught him about the USA's confusing government.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_aa2aef0e089a4da6aefe25dbcca8b10a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_be1062597e564c62b098ed1a840e466a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6d01e91632514d92878005a901353e16~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0dee95f5f0dc4c149e12dda657a1ccb7~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e40e408a6a0e4f6f94ce401504628ae6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_fb7c76e64d944a15a67b0d24d71cce5f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f8f8537e39814e828bd2ee7fb35235ad~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_842c732f93b84bd5aece11cc13ae96ed~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b8b7e2e0481d414698ea37a9b216690e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7c84d58fc4aa4725b487c48235396336~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5e0f0f81ce9f444bb9a04cae206a77d0~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_17896f3e90e74befa7133b5a3ac8a37d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0607009a35df49219a4a1d1b5d9021bd~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0dbedd609233413b8265e239c4552d74~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9e23ae25964c439c88de76aecb961dde~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5c21fe2aeea74a1fa8e4e848e785301c~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>
The Land of Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade - Ma'an, Jordan
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
But we didn't find the holy grail! Al Khazneh (the temple housing the grail in the movie) is not very big inside. The movie lies! Surprise? But it was definitely one of the coolest things we've seen so far. Quick facts (I don't take any responsibility for being wrong about these. Laura and I aren't very good at listening to guides): Al Khazneh, or "The Treasury" is actually a mausoleum in the center of Petra, Jordan. Petra is an ancient city hand-carved out of sandstone. There is only one<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_652e7f38cc41467498a7593be261cd55%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/05/The-Land-of-Indiana-Jones-and-the-Last-Crusade---Maan-Jordan
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/05/The-Land-of-Indiana-Jones-and-the-Last-Crusade---Maan-Jordan
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>But we didn't find the holy grail! Al Khazneh (the temple housing the grail in the movie) is not very big inside. The movie lies! Surprise? But it was definitely one of the coolest things we've seen so far. Quick facts (I don't take any responsibility for being wrong about these. Laura and
]]>
<![CDATA[
I aren't very good at listening to guides): Al Khazneh, or &quot;The Treasury&quot; is actually a mausoleum in the center of Petra, Jordan. Petra is an ancient city hand-carved out of sandstone. There is only one entrance to the city via a long and winding canyon. This made it easy to protect. It was also a major economic hub for the area. The city has passed through many people groups over time. The Nabataeans were the first, and the ones who did most of the carving, including the Al Khazneh. Then they were taken over by the Romans (of course). The Roman architecture in Petra is more &quot;built&quot; rather than &quot;carved&quot;. More recently, the Beduins have occupied the area and are the people selling you tourist junk or trying to get you to ride their camels. Due to multiple earthquakes, a good chunk of the city is buried underground/destroyed. The city had its own aqueduct system, a theatre, and tons of &quot;grave caves&quot; (I can't remember the proper name). Basically the whole time you're saying, &quot;How did they carve that?&quot;. It's awesome. Highly recommended from Laura and I. After Petra we caught an all you can eat buffet (included with the tour). I had probably 100 lamb meatballs with spaghetti. I'm officially converted from beef to lamb when it comes to meatballs. Cows rejoice! Sorry vegetarians. It's soooo good. After lunch we took a 2 hour journey back to the Jordan-Israeli boarder where we met our Israeli friends who took a trip down to Eilat for the weekend to go scuba diving. Of course we had to partake! The area is famous for it.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_652e7f38cc41467498a7593be261cd55~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_baae3167a30f428b921a02219bb6f384~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9c5e74691a8d4aa78754303ae68a57d9~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d13426799c1249c8b82fe676714c3efc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0f2a9987796f4a0db2aa26ef589554d8~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b8a872cd8a0349f2a6219cb4b4a32a9b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a37aff967b7340dbbac372f5c86cf17e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_bc14e82265064fbeb718b7f8d2c21408~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_54e24dafb1514abd9ac4b9b075f4a605~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5c2ecdf0b9974910b49acfaee31ddb6d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_886266f8cd8c4b2aa246beeb6a0e1295~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3ae2134e959f4366b403d79cbf200938~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2218cd2f23f441d9a5bf2842198a23be~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0591c403144e4af69860e1275390103a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7bc88f0b5b2d44b7813a486762ac4949~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_08779229b4a844ea9a41ef9d7cfcee5d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a95c071bb46a432196dcd3b8545debca~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2041de4efa3b488cabcb929d00fc1b0f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e6dbf77129cc4b3cbbf6285f42dcf81e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9e2b9df257234e5387a45d36822aa7ff~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aqaba: Welcome to Jordan - Aqaba, Galilee, Jordan</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
From Jerusalem we took the 7AM bus south to the city of Eliat, next to the Red Sea. We then spent the day catching up on some reading, waiting for a 6PM pickup for our tour to Petra, Jordan. We researched and found that a tour group was cheaper than going alone, and spending the night before the tour in Aqaba, Jordan saved even more on the park entrance fee to Petra ($75 instead of $150). After avoiding a scamming taxi driver (with the tour company) who was trying to charge us a $15 fee for<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2d403efddf62465a8511ccf71c7c3417%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/03/Aqaba-Welcome-to-Jordan---Aqaba-Galilee-Jordan
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/03/Aqaba-Welcome-to-Jordan---Aqaba-Galilee-Jordan
</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>From Jerusalem we took the 7AM bus south to the city of Eliat, next to the Red Sea. We then spent the day catching up on some reading, waiting for a 6PM pickup for our tour to Petra, Jordan. We researched and found that a tour group was cheaper than going alone, and spending the night before the tour in Aqaba, Jordan saved even more on the park entrance fee to Petra ($75 instead of $150). After avoiding a scamming taxi driver (with the tour company) who was trying to charge us a $15 fee for paying in local Israeli sheckles instead of dollars, we crossed the border into Jordan on foot. We were greeted by our guide on the other side, who had to talk to the head honcho of the taxi monopoly (in Jordan) and show him the stickers on our shirts in order to pass. We met a friendly couple at the border who wanted to catch a ride with us, but our guide explained that the taxi company does not allow anyone to drive with a tour company unless they have a sticker and also a guide present. Everyone else has to pay hefty transport fees, and groups are required to split up to be only one person per taxi. This is part of the reason we didn't try to go to Petra on our own... Mark and I entered the giant tourist bus and learned that we were the only ones staying overnight before the tour. We were brought to our downtown Aqaba hotel and told to be in the lobby at 8:30 AM. After seeing our beautiful room (that unfortunately smelled of smoke - everyone smokes in Jordan) and hearing about the wonderful breakfast buffet, we walked to the guide-recommended hummus restaurant up the street. Hummus is famous in Jordan, and for good reason. We were also served fresh orange juice, french fries and shwarma/cheese burritos. YUM. Our extremely friendly waiter refused our tip, but after some insistence gave in and said he would give the tip to someone who needs it (we'll take him for his word). Then we tried the local beer before going for a walk. Surprisingly, the Islamic state of Jordan does have beer. We were pleasantly surprised by how nice all the locals were. One teenager literally chauffered us across traffic, while another man in a car leaned out his window and apologized when the driver didn't stop for us. Mark also made friends with a group of four teenage boys, who stopped their bikes to say &quot;welcome to Jordan&quot; and small talk. Everyone says &quot;you are welcome in Jordan&quot;. We ran into a few camels on the sidewalks, and also a funny 11-year-old kid who started chasing us with a box of goods, jabbering in Jordanian. When Mark told him, &quot;I bet you're trying to sell me something&quot;, his response was &quot;YES! Very good!&quot;. Then he offered us a cigarette. Again, everyone smokes. We saw the Red Sea from the Jordanian side before turning in for the night.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2d403efddf62465a8511ccf71c7c3417~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7a886018ce6e44769cf5d413b7e57572~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Annoying Day - Jerusalem, Galilee, Israel</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Our last day in Jerusalem was a mess. We tried to see the sights that had so-far eluded our schedule, including the Dome of the Rock (a holy place for Muslims and Jews), and the location where Jesus was betrayed in the Garden of Gethsemane. Unfortunately both were closed for lunch from 12-2:30. We got lunch and did a bit of shopping / meandering to kill time. At 2:30 we tried four security points, all refusing us entry to the Dome of the Rock. One that we had entered earlier in the week now held<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a883b5fe6a184dd380523a898797f01c%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/02/Annoying-Day---Jerusalem-Galilee-Israel
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/04/02/Annoying-Day---Jerusalem-Galilee-Israel
</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 17:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Our last day in Jerusalem was a mess. We tried to see the sights that had so-far eluded our schedule, including the Dome of the Rock (a holy place for Muslims and Jews), and the location where Jesus was betrayed in the Garden of Gethsemane. Unfortunately both were closed for lunch from 12-2:30. We got lunch and did a bit of shopping / meandering to kill time. At 2:30 we tried four security points, all refusing us entry to the Dome of the Rock. One that we had entered earlier in the week now held a guard that informed us it was no longer an entry point. One held about 300 school kids. Another two only let in Muslims. We finally made it inside with 45 minutes before closing for the day. Listening to our audio tour on warp speed, we almost finished before being rudely forced out of the compound. We then went to the place Jesus was likely betrayed, and also visited the Church of Dominus Flevit, one of my favorite churches. It overlooked Jerusalem on the Mount of Olives, was small and cozy, and had great acoustics. From there we booked it to the light rial to see the Holocaust museum before closing. Upon arrival 30 minutes later, we were told that even though their sign and website say closing is at 5, they don't let anyone enter past 4, almost exactly when we arrived. We were, however, allowed to see the hall of remembrance for children, a small art exhibit, and a lecture hall. The hall of remembrance for children was one of the most impactful that we had ever seen. The room was filled with mirrors, reflecting candle flames throughout the whole room. As you walked through the maze, children's' names were read, along with their countries and age of death. We were sad to not see the rest of the museum, but still glad we came. Tired and annoyed about the day, we headed back to Old City. The post office we needed to visit was closed, so we decided to get ice cream. Unfortunately they didn't take credit card, and after getting cash we were told that we couldn't eat in the store because prices are different for dine-in. The ice cream was OK, but disappointing compared to the amazing concoction we were given in Tel Aviv. For our last night in Jerusalem we decided to sleep on the roof of a youth hostel in Old Jerusalem. It had amazing views, and came complete with mattress and fresh blankets. Thankfully we had our sleeping bags, too, because between the wind and the cold that had been slowly creeping in all week, it was about 40 degrees. We were warm enough, and able to get up at 5:30 to catch our bus to Eilat.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7a886018ce6e44769cf5d413b7e57572~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2d403efddf62465a8511ccf71c7c3417~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a883b5fe6a184dd380523a898797f01c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8f9cc2a654aa4ca5b906993f5e8cb1dc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3392a7e892cf4955ab81e914f167efa4~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_6ce96388e9eb49448a170bfeca5d87ee~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_fcf6e6ff9a8d462399b65fb82fdcc89a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_24660a9351974a4eabbe2bac57eb0e40~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_ca74c2ed2737450bb00c09613eeb91ec~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_207f4ac1eebd4f65af24e71fc169ed60~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b4ebea7bba294a9e8ea4b18cbc226edf~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f0330eef029e4aa0b62ec0b40d0e181e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d3a9ff2491b249d0bdd933765ff52938~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>
All Things Good Come From Nazareth - Nazareth, Galilee, Israel
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We booked our second guided Israel tour, jumping into a van with a bunch of Americans and Canadians to go up north to Nazareth. Our guide was more fluent in german than english. This meant that almost every english sentence he started would inevitably end up in enthusiastic and lengthly german. Thankfully at least the german-speaking half of our group could understand! On the drive we also saw the future location of Armageddon (not the 1998 film), and the Mount of Transfiguration. We stopped at<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_688f3663b39e416a9cff805126a5d411%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/31/All-Things-Good-Come-From-Nazareth---Nazareth-Galilee-Israel
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/31/All-Things-Good-Come-From-Nazareth---Nazareth-Galilee-Israel
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 17:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We booked our second guided Israel tour, jumping into a van with a bunch of Americans and Canadians to go up north to Nazareth. Our guide was more fluent in german than english. This meant that almost every english sentence he started would inevitably end up in enthusiastic and lengthly german. Thankfully at least the german-speaking half of our group could understand! On the drive we also saw the future location of Armageddon (not the 1998 film), and the Mount of Transfiguration. We stopped at numerous churches, one with beautiful mosaic art pieces donning the walls, donated from different countries. Don't worry, the USA's contribution was the coolest. We saw St. Peter's house (an impressive site of excavated ruins), and an ancient house that was more like a maze of underground caves that is said to have been Mary and Joseph's. We tried to walk on water at the beautiful Sea of Galilee, and of course failed miserably. We also stopped at the Jordan River, and I had Mark baptize me. Might as well get baptized where Jesus did huh? Unfortunately the water was not beautiful like the Sea of Galilee, but rather cold, green, and full of GIANT fish! Still awesome.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_688f3663b39e416a9cff805126a5d411~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d416238af3744c4082c0eeec507bc827~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_f7d4c447f2194e07bbffaef94ad59b11~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7fddd6ce380d4f6aa048d2dad14bf743~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_00221191dbe348439fe3ec6c25483ed6~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5c4bb8e8970344ab9fc2ee1501d6b115~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9c77bc01d96e40c3875a4dc47527cb38~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9cab730941bc4b8ab7e7e77e8e6c87c3~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_64874582f2e64f068d014578fdaa8073~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9ad91ffd7c6845beb5dbc9043d39b31e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_564418c188134011969df9039da6d46c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b0415be9bbac411986efded59474dbd3~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7b8c89a3aef847378681ba16587d1b84~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_61b80fde219d437bb80261f9d8b025a8~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_85a9622bf57743d2a8fbb44aec35fe1a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_bea75134dfef4c0787dd099194a5c998~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d58cfbb1f45c4415ae44445daeecdb41~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_166ad593efd34ce3acf7fd5caaf95f2a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_df42f8e237624ee694af9edf29973bb1~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>
O Little Town of Bethlehem - Bethlehem, Jerusalem, West Bank and Gaza
</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Our visit to Bethlehem fell on a Sunday, so we thought we'd check out a church service in Jerusalem before catching the bus. Walking through the old city, we found Christ Church - the oldest Protestant church in the Middle East. This church also had awesome acoustics so it was fun to sing in there with everyone. And the congregation was truly international, which made it even better. Boulder, Colorado would be jealous of our diversity. After church, we caught the bus to Bethlehem in the West<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_43d6fe2e02a348eaaf5a9aba3cc408a8%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/30/O-Little-Town-of-Bethlehem---Bethlehem-Jerusalem-West-Bank-and-Gaza
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/30/O-Little-Town-of-Bethlehem---Bethlehem-Jerusalem-West-Bank-and-Gaza
</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Our visit to Bethlehem fell on a Sunday, so we thought we'd check out a church service in Jerusalem before catching the bus. Walking through the old city, we found Christ Church - the oldest Protestant church in the Middle East. This church also had awesome acoustics so it was fun to sing in there with everyone. And the congregation was truly international, which made it even better. Boulder, Colorado would be jealous of our diversity. After church, we caught the bus to Bethlehem in the West Bank, following advice from a friendly American couple at church who work at the Garden Tomb. It definitely has a different feel than Israel proper. If anything, most of the writing is in Arabic rather than Hebrew. Laura and I grabbed our usual shawarma burritos and then moseyed our way over to the Church of Nativity. It was kind of disappointing... Church clergy yell, &quot;Silence!&quot; at all of the tourists while other clergy sing hymns in the corner. But you're not allowed to watch them... I'll refrain from being too harsh on them, but I guess Laura and I have different views on how God works. A little upset, Laura and I left to go check out the &quot;Israeli West Bank Barrier,&quot; a ginormous concrete wall that Israel has constructed to separate Israel from Palestine. It's dotted with security cameras and guard towers. It looks like a maximum security prison perimeter. Israel argues that the wall is necessary in order to protect its citizens from Palestinian terrorist attacks. Palestinians call it the &quot;Apartheid Wall.&quot; Some tourists and I were talking to a Palestinian who had his house next to the wall. He was complaining that he is scared to do anything because &quot;big brother&quot; is always watching. Either way, it's a tourist attraction now because the Palestinian side of it is covered with graffiti art. The famous graffiti artist, Banksy, has even left his mark. I was taking a picture of Laura in front of the wall, and all of a sudden, SMASH! A flaming bottle of gasoline blew up down the wall from me. Laura and I quickly moved away from the fire and turned around to see six or so Palestinians throwing makeshift &quot;weapons&quot; (some flaming bottles and rocks) over the wall to the Israeli side. After they unloaded their arsenal, they quickly retreated. Shortly thereafter a squad of soldiers from the Israeli army crossed over with riot gear on. Unfortunately I didn't get any good pictures because Laura and I were more concerned about our safety than being the next LIFE magazine photographer. But as we were walking later, we noticed that our eyes were tearing up and found out that the Israeli's had hit them with tear gas. The area we were in is a tourist area with tourist busses coming and going all the time. So it goes to show how real the conflict is... After the fiasco Laura and I headed straight back to Israel proper through an &quot;immigration gate&quot; in the wall and took the first bus back to Jerusalem. It was kind of funny because the only people walking through were a few &quot;approved&quot; Palestinians, a group of Christian pastors, and us. Probably one of the weirder border crossings we've had. And come to think of it, I'm glad we didn't tell anyone in Bethlehem that we were American.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_009fd031da39437fb837ce171887e25b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4d7f17e7c87d48598c0a120be1215cf0~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_61a4bd3ebc2f4e71b48993239b91d71a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b493063b5a7a48d695810fe7ece8da39~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_45f2393c9e38437fa61e7ab6a6094280~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d1db53930ed44d8db8337e4cd5d1d063~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_86e396998ef8462e95c963d3389ada75~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_8ca83cd26ba94239aca7d127054686e4~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_66bfb8edeaa84d1283acbcd4c82eb4d0~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_5e596d088c3b4a4890ffdab12b23db41~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_59b5af2a52584925be64913efc4c628c~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d5079f5f37a5431eacff630f5adfcc43~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_a3ba072417594b8ba6cb5de000380164~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_faad93cd94a04bdfa1bfe806b85b50bd~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e96dbd934300483f9408717595db0178~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d468f408e55e4ccda899d07f188a7516~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e2d5cc08f4824c3091c74574af72f924~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_79143f4655d64a69a6ec6138a2e85d0f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_43d6fe2e02a348eaaf5a9aba3cc408a8~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1604bddb191945f4adea7965c7839788~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Birthday - Ein Gedi, Dead Sea Region, Israe</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
We booked a tour to go to Masada Fort and the Dead Sea for my birthday. The day started rough, with 3 Imodium pills, but quickly improved. Our tour was led in both Spanish and English; it was a small gift in itself to get to practice some Spanish. Our first stop was a bathroom break that happened to also be a Dead Sea cosmetics shop. After an infomercial and a dose of patience, we were on our way again. The drive led us past Qumran - where the Dead Sea Scrolls were found. Unfortunately we
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/29/Birthday---Ein-Gedi-Dead-Sea-Region-Israe
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/29/Birthday---Ein-Gedi-Dead-Sea-Region-Israe
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>We booked a tour to go to Masada Fort and the Dead Sea for my birthday. The day started rough, with 3 Imodium pills, but quickly improved. Our tour was led in both Spanish and English; it was a small gift in itself to get to practice some Spanish. Our first stop was a bathroom break that happened to also be a Dead Sea cosmetics shop. After an infomercial and a dose of patience, we were on our way again. The drive led us past Qumran - where the Dead Sea Scrolls were found. Unfortunately we weren't able to explore the caves in hopes of finding more treasures. Masada Fort, perched on top of a steep desert cliff, can be hiked to in the blazing sun on foot or by effortless gondola ride. Our tour, thankfully, included the gondola ride. The fort was built by King Herod as an escape refuge in case any of his many enemies went after him. He ended up dying before utilizing the beautifully constructed desert utopia, complete with steam room, cold room, food storage, water cisterns to feed thousands, and temple. Hundreds of years later, when the Romans were taking over the area, a thousand Jews sought refuge in the abandoned fort. The Romans took three years to build a ramp to the compound and force their way in. The night before they arrived, however, the men inside killed their wives and children, before killing eachother. They decided it was better to die than be slaves of the Romans. Apparently there is a movie about the whole thing...I intend to find it. After all the time in the scorching sun we were ready to cover ourselves in mud and take a dip in the Dead Sea. It is 10x saltier than any ocean, making it impossible to sink. Literally. Mark and I had never been able to float, but found ourselves laughing and flailing in the water, amazed at our new buoyancy. You could stand straight up, feet not touching the bottom, and bob, head clear out of the water. The only bad part about all this fun is the terrible effects of the saltwater on your eyes and mouth. Everyone was careful to keep their heads dry to avoid, what felt like fire on your face. Mark and I both got a small taste of the salty water and did our best not to cry. There was also a nearby hot spring to warm up in. It was all wonderful. So wonderful. Exhausted after a long day, we showered and lay motionless in our room for awhile, recovering. Then Mark put on his schnazzy polo shirt and made me get into a dress for a nice dinner, recommended by Trip Advisor. We had delicious kebabs and red wine, the perfect way to end a wonderful birthday.</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jerusalem - Jerusalem, Israel</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Jerusalem was our home base to make trips out to other parts of Israel. We found a hotel/hostel combo about a block from the Damascus Gate (north gate) of Old Jerusalem to call home base. There are eight gates into/out of the Old City. From here we spent our first two days exploring the old city. We visited the Mount of Olives, and also the Garden Tomb, our favorite place in Israel. The friendly people in the garden were a breath of fresh air from the blunt, harsh locals in town. Jesus is<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_51db53c120c74cc28cf77a49d25862fc%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/28/Jerusalem---Jerusalem-Israel
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/28/Jerusalem---Jerusalem-Israel
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 17:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Jerusalem was our home base to make trips out to other parts of Israel. We found a hotel/hostel combo about a block from the Damascus Gate (north gate) of Old Jerusalem to call home base. There are eight gates into/out of the Old City. From here we spent our first two days exploring the old city. We visited the Mount of Olives, and also the Garden Tomb, our favorite place in Israel. The friendly people in the garden were a breath of fresh air from the blunt, harsh locals in town. Jesus is thought to have been crucified by nearby Skull Rock, a place easily visible from the ancient main road (the rock really does look just like a skull) and buried in a nearby cave. The next day we walked the Via Delarosa (the path Jesus took the day he was crucified). We also spent time at St. Anne's Church, which is beautiful and has perfect acoustics (as demonstrated by an epic tour group from Georgia - the country). Mark and I's solo was lacking, but it was amazing to hear the echo - it was like there were 6 of me! Nearby there are ruins that cover where the pool of Bethseda once was. It was really cool, too! We found free audio tours with maps courtesy of the Jerusalem Development Authority, which turned out to be surprisingly good. We loved learning the history of the old places - it really made ancient Biblical story locations come to life and help with the picture of geography and events in the early years BC. The downside was how strict and stark a lot of the churches felt. Many called for &quot;silence&quot; or felt unwelcoming or were putting excessive emphasis on things rather than God. &quot;The rock where Jesus likely fell carrying his cross&quot; or &quot;The birthplace of Mary&quot; had swarms of people gathered to touch and lay souvenirs and scarves on them, to soak up some holiness. At the Church of the Holy Sepulcher, where many think Jesus was killed and buried, the numerous religious groups that share the church often fight, causing police to be on call. This is why visiting the Garden Tomb was particularly refreshing. The staff who volunteer there focus on Jesus himself (historically and spiritually), rather than being caught up in religious tradition and superstition. Every morning we would eat the included breakfast at our hostel. It was great - pita bread, hummus, hard boiled eggs, salads, tea, coffee...the works. Lunch was a chicken shwarma or falafel lafa (giant Israeli burrito). Dinner was the same, accompanied by a ton of fresh fruit from the market. When you can get a kilo of the juiciest strawberries on the planet for $1.50, it's literally impossible to say no. On more side note: people walk all over in Israel with big guns. They aren't always wearing uniforms and often hold the trigger while they walk. I try not to to mess with anyone.</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_51db53c120c74cc28cf77a49d25862fc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_39b2136626b246a6819d19a6de3322fc~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_fa41541a7ac24cffac712d5941ff25e7~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_b0ed0e9cb58e49d494067e96bae127d7~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e6b7c34d4efa4d4daa6fa504903b5506~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_284da710aee6416c9ad2cfb036be8201~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_231e55ffeba141bc8b319835a5486f00~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9f3c8076f0b5449980f5a32f79f5b13a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2f4eeb4d2a074e0ab71b9f3a4cf2e58d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_1911aec265cd42e192789d9f079a1a2e~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4f5ed1d3f40f47c88fa8f30d4601bf79~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_aa208c185d6947d39ae8ba943ea87d10~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c8a87129aeaf42d3953f8dc3a22390b0~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_bca3db1947794d188bf03602fa38d101~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c55fc4b6824446dc9213adecad5a9bc2~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_eaca30889ed94315a75174469f016afb~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2cc6e0a9ef884eb2a16a0942357c79fe~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_9b5d95051511486fa74ab6f29b91737d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_771a5bbb2521413988dd338ffea548e8~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_fc53af8235fb4c2ba7020abef99704c4~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Warm Greeting - Tel Aviv, Jerusalem, Israel</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Our trip from Kathmandu, Nepal to Tel Aviv, Israel consisted of a 17-hour layover in Doha, Qatar, followed by the most intense security I have ever seen in Amman, Jordan. after over 35 hours of travel we were greeted at the Tel Aviv airport by Lev, a really nice Russian who has been living in Israel for the last 15 years. He and his girlfriend, Natalka, offered to host us in their downtown apartment. We were absolutely spoiled by a nice view from the enclosed balcony we called home, as well as<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_28653522653344c697cfa1cdcdfe2c7b%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Laura</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/27/A-Warm-Greeting---Tel-Aviv-Jerusalem-Israel
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/27/A-Warm-Greeting---Tel-Aviv-Jerusalem-Israel
</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 17:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Our trip from Kathmandu, Nepal to Tel Aviv, Israel consisted of a 17-hour layover in Doha, Qatar, followed by the most intense security I have ever seen in Amman, Jordan. after over 35 hours of travel we were greeted at the Tel Aviv airport by Lev, a really nice Russian who has been living in Israel for the last 15 years. He and his girlfriend, Natalka, offered to host us in their downtown apartment. We were absolutely spoiled by a nice view from the enclosed balcony we called home, as well as home-cooked meals four times a day (yes, four). Natalka is Ukranian and an amazing cook. She made us Ukranian potato cakes, muffins, hummus, loads of broccoli and fresh vegetables, eggs, salads...the list goes on and on. We (and they) thought it was funny that they were Russian and Ukranian, considering recent current events. Both thought Putin should back off. Lev had to work at Dell during the days, and Natalka (who was a fashion designer in Ukraine) had computer design classes at a local college on Monday, so Mark and I explored on our own. We walked the half hour to the beach, marveled at all the jellyfish dead on the shore, and made our way toward Old Jaffa, the old area of Tel Aviv. We explored the &quot;hipster&quot; part of town, winding through flea markets and antique stores before wandering back home. That night we all went out for 'sabih' (sure I didn't spell that right), a vegetarian pita concoction made with eggplant. It was excellent. Lev and Natalka took us on a walking tour of their downtown area, including a visit to a a new missile defense system that was made to shoot down home-made rockets sent in the air from Palestine. Business as usual. After chowing down on some macadamia nut Hagan-Dazs ice cream, we fell easily into bed. The next day Mark and I were surprised with a beautiful breakfast. Also, Natalka told us that she could join us for the day. She took us through a different area of town in Old Jaffa, where she showed us the old streets, a floating tree suspended by cables, and one of oldest port in the world. Apparently, Jaffa Port is where Jonah took off in the &quot;Jonah and the Whale&quot; Bible story. Most importantly she showed us the best ice cream place in town, which is a strong contender for the best of our lives. After dinner we sat down to watch &quot;The Barber of Siberia&quot;, a hilarious Russian movie, on Lev's giant projector screen. The next morning Mark and I took the bus to Jerusalem, with plans to meet our friends for some scuba diving at the Red Sea next week!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0486fa9048ce43fbbe5e04cfbafa88ba~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_c5f7477418e7414a969c1a6167fd28d0~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_095901900afa4757b603bd5d9483b12f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_7c532c08e91e4de0aba847328bed51e3~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_dd45ea67984444eabca36b834a781154~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_3b60688d177545a99fcb8db297da80d2~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_50499e87a480462d9df19e402eb73cb2~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_28653522653344c697cfa1cdcdfe2c7b~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_fe00b36ef91b4759a2c7b67c9299ac76~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_d68c910e63eb483a92575652f4f63d9d~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_93384ae059a64b96b61704b726f4fabe~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_4552237e76c14fca8b3f053772fc20d7~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_70f2d1939c334122872cbe6494db396a~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_03c1ec72ffdb40dc97ed0f6ca100e78f~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0595ba254247491a9ea95514e14500b5~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_2c3065c879ea4c6280b5f34beb17bb38~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_af6bf85b8db84f5c8af7ace45422e3ae~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_de7013bd28c649808cd3236d3392f366~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_e985616a9f1c4798a04d59573a917dfa~mv2.jpg"/><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_aedb8b5cf71e44b79efb7287afb952bd~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>35 hours of transit deserves a post - Doha, Qatar</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
From Nepal to Tel Aviv, we had to stop in Doha, Qatar and Amman, Jordan. We've heard rumors from other travelers that Qatar Airlines "hooks up" a hotel/food for their customers when they have an 8+ hour layover. Ours was 17 hours, so we had our fingers crossed! We landed and an airline representative told us to go upstairs and talk to the customer service desk who would give us a hotel. Woohoo! We were stoked. Once we got to the desk, we gave the lady our boarding cards and then she immediately<img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0c886d7605da43b6ac9adde940a095a6%7Emv2.jpg"/>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/24/35-hours-of-transit-deserves-a-post---Doha-Qatar
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/24/35-hours-of-transit-deserves-a-post---Doha-Qatar
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 17:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>From Nepal to Tel Aviv, we had to stop in Doha, Qatar and Amman, Jordan. We've heard rumors from other travelers that Qatar Airlines &quot;hooks up&quot; a hotel/food for their customers when they have an 8+ hour layover. Ours was 17 hours, so we had our fingers crossed! We landed and an airline representative told us to go upstairs and talk to the customer service desk who would give us a hotel. Woohoo! We were stoked. Once we got to the desk, we gave the lady our boarding cards and then she immediately started shaking her head. Uh oh... Apparently this sort of privilege is only honored if you take the two closest possible flights and it still amounts to an 8+ hour layover. Because we booked the cheapest option, this was not the case for us. 17 hours layover in the airport, ohhhhh yeaaaa..... We thought about leaving and checking out the city but the entry VISA was about $40 per person. Not really worth it for a few hours. From what we saw, the place looks like a small Dubai. They're dropping their dough on fancy hotels and expensive restaurants to try to encourage tourism before their oil money runs out. From Qatar we stopped in Amman, because Qatar doesn't fly directly to Israel (due to their relationship). In Amman, we were led by security down a bunch of back doors and corridors where we held in a small hallway and handed off to Israeli security. Their security is (understandably) rediculous. Each passenger is interviewed and their baggage is checked by hand. Laura and I felt like criminals and had to keep reminding ourselves that we didn't do anything wrong. I also noticed that they kept and Israeli guy in the line with us as we each waited our turn. He was looking around, profiling everybody to see if anyone looked like they were up to no good. Luckily, our long blonde hair didn't raise any flags. Finally, after a 35 minute flight, we landed in Tel Aviv! Holy Land Ho!</div><img src="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/fdb926_0c886d7605da43b6ac9adde940a095a6~mv2.jpg"/></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>VIDEO: Part 2 of Laura and I's dancing skillz.</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[
Copy and paste this into your browser! http://youtu.be/G2_a9STvLeU Miss part 1? http://youtu.be/1wEK9AXv56Q
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
<link>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/23/VIDEO-Part-2-of-Laura-and-Is-dancing-skillz
</link>
<guid>
https://lbhasemeyer.wixsite.com/hasemeyer/single-post/2014/03/23/VIDEO-Part-2-of-Laura-and-Is-dancing-skillz
</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[
<div><div>Copy and paste this into your browser! http://youtu.be/G2_a9STvLeU Miss part 1? http://youtu.be/1wEK9AXv56Q</div></div>
]]>
</content:encoded>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
